[
    {
        "question" : "A's age after 15 years would be equal to 5 times his age 5 years ago. Find his age 3 years hence.",
        "answer" : "13 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The product of the ages of A and B is 240. If twice the age of B is more than A’s age by 4 years, what was B’s age 2 years ago?",
        "answer" : "10 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : " The present age of a mother is 3 years more than three times the age of her daughter. Three years hence, the mother’s age will be 10 years more than twice the age of the daughter. Find the present age of the mother.",
        "answer" : "33 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio of present ages of A and B is 6 : 7. Five years hence, this ratio would become 7 : 8. Find the present age of A and B.",
        "answer" : "35 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Sum of the age of 4 children born at interval of 4 years is 36. What is the age of youngest child?",
        "answer" : "3 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A is 5 years older than B who is thrice as old as C. If the total of ages of A, B and C is 40, then how old is C ?",
        "answer" : "5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Present age of Vinod and Ashok are in ratio of 3:4 respectively. After 5 years, the ratio of their ages becomes 7:9 respectively. What is Ashok’s present age is ?",
        "answer" : "40 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "At present father’s age is thrice of son’s age. After 15 years father’s age will be double of son’s age. What is son’s present age?",
        "answer" : "15 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "At present father’s age is thrice of son’s age. After 15 years father’s age will be double of son’s age. What is son’s present age?",
        "answer" : "15 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "At present, the ratio between ages of Ram and Shyam is 6:5 respectively. After 7 years, Shyam’s age will be 32 years. What is the present age of Ram?",
        "answer" : "30"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The present ages of A, B and C are in proportions 4:5:9. Nine years ago, sum of their ages was 45 years. Find their present ages in years",
        "answer" : "16, 20, 36"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person’s present age is one third of the age of his mother. After 12 years, his age will be one half of the age of his mother. What is present age of his mother?",
        "answer" : "36"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A is as older than B as he is younger than C.If the sum of ages of B and C is 68 years. What is the present age of A?",
        "answer" : "34 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "After 15 years, Paul’s age will be 5 times his age 5 years back. Find out his present age.",
        "answer" : "10 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Sam is 16 years older than Peter. If 6 years back, Sam's age was 3 times Peter's age, what are their present ages?",
        "answer" : "14 and 30 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Cooper's present age is 3 years more than thrice Max's present age. After 3 years, Cooper's age will 10 years more than twice Max's age. What is Cooper's present age?",
        "answer" : "33 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The age of a father was 4 times his son’s age 8 years back. After 8 years, the father will be twice as old as his son. Find out the present ages of father and son.",
        "answer" : "16 and 40 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "6:7 is the ratio of Michael's and Rosan‘s ages one year back. The ratio will become 7:8 in four years. Calculate the present age of Rosan.",
        "answer" : "36 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "5 years ago age of Ram was 50 % less than Shyam’s age. If the ratio of Shyam’s present age to Ram’s present age 4:3. What will be Ram’s age after 7.5 years?",
        "answer" : "15 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "5 years ago the ratio of Shyam’s age to Ram’s age is 3:2. If Ram’s present age is 25% less than Shyam’s present age. What will be Ram’s age after 10 years?",
        "answer" : "25 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Meena will be 5 times his age 5 years back, after 15 years. What is the present age of Meena?",
        "answer" : "10 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "boy is older than girl by 7 years. If the ratio of ages of boy:girl is 9:7, what is the age of boy?",
        "answer" : "31.5 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The present ages of Ram and Shyam are in the ratio 6:7. If Shyam is 4 years older than Ram, after 4 years what will be the ratio of their ages?",
        "answer" : "7:8"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If difference of ages of Ram and Shyam is 16 years. If 6 year ago, the Ram’s age is 3 times as old the Shyam, What are Ram and Shyam's respective present ages?",
        "answer" : "14,30"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The sum of the ages of a mother and daughter is 45 years. 5 years ago, the product of their ages was 30 times the daughter's age at that time. What is the present age of mother?",
        "answer" : "35"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The sum of the ages of a mother and daughter is 45 years. 5 years ago, the product of their ages was 30 times the daughter's age at that time. What is the present age of daughter?",
        "answer" : "10"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ram age was half of Shaym’s age, 10 years ago. If the ratio of their present ages is 3:5, what is the sum of their ages at present?",
        "answer" : "80"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The Sum of ages of Seeta and Geeta is 12 years less than the sum of ages of Geeta and Ina. By how many years Ina is older than Seeta?",
        "answer" : "12"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ages of A and B differ by 16 years. 6 years ago, the elder one was 3 times as old as the younger one. What is present ages of the elder person?",
        "answer" : "30"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ram and Shyam’s ages are in the ratio between 4:3. After 6 Years age of Ram will be 26 years. What is present age of Shyam?",
        "answer" : "15"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A father said his son , ' I was as old as you are at present at the time of your birth '. If the father age is 38 now, the son age 5 years back was :",
        "answer" : "14"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In 10 years, A will be twice as old as B was 10 years ago. If A is now 9 years older than B, the present age of B is :",
        "answer" : "39"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The total age of A and B is 12 years more than the total age of B and C. C is how many years younger than A ?",
        "answer" : "12"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio of the present ages of P and Q is 3 : 4. Five years ago, the ratio of their ages was 5 : 7. Find their present ages.",
        "answer" : "40"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The age of a man is 4 times of his son. Five years ago, the man was nine times old as his son was at that time. The present age of man is?",
        "answer" : "8"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The sum of the present ages of a father and his son is 60 years. five years ago, father's age was four times the age of the son. so now the son's age will be:",
        "answer" : "15"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Rajeev's age after 15 years will be 5 times his age 5 years back. What is the present age of rajeev?",
        "answer" : "10"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The average age of a group of 10 students is 15 years. When 5 more students join the group, the average age increase by 1 year. The average age of the new students is?",
        "answer" : "18 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The sum of the present ages of two persons A and B is 60. If the age of A is twice that of B, find the sum of their ages 5 years hence.",
        "answer" : "70"
    },
    {
        "question" : "'I am five times as old as you were, when I was as old as you are', said a man to his son. Find out their present ages, if the sum of their ages is 64 years ?",
        "answer" : " Father = 40; Son =24"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What is the age of Teja? A: Four years ago, Raju was as old as Teja is at present.B: Sita’s present age is two times of Raju’s present age.C: The average age of Teja and Sita is 19 years.",
        "answer" : "Teja = 10yrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The average age of a class is 15.8 years. The average age of the boys in the class is 16.4 years and that of the girls is 15.4 years. What is the ratio of boys to girls in the class ?",
        "answer" : "2:3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If 6 years are subtracted from the present age of Arun and the remainder is divided by 18, then the present age of his grandson Gokul is obtained. If Gokul is 2 years younger to Madan whose age is 5 years, then what is the age of Arun ?",
        "answer" : "60 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person's present age is two-fifth of the age of his mother. After 8 years, he will be one-half of the age of his mother. How old is the mother at present ?",
        "answer" : "40 yrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ages of Krish and Vaibhav are in the proportion of 3 : 5. After 9 years, the proportion of their ages will be 3 : 4. Then the current age of Vaibhav is:",
        "answer" : "15 yrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio of the father's age to the son's age is 3 : 1. The product of their ages is 147. The ratio of their ages after 5 years will be?",
        "answer" : "13 : 6"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The present average age of a family of five members is 26 years. If the present age of the youngest member in the family is ten years, then what was the average age of the family at the time of the birth of the youngest member ? (Assume no death occurred in the family since the birth of the youngest)",
        "answer" : " 20 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Eight years ago, Ajay's age was 4/3 times that of Vijay. Eight years hence, Ajay's age will be 6/5 times that of Vijay. What is the present age of Ajay ?",
        "answer" : "40 yrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "he ages of X and Y are in the proportion of 6:5 and total of their ages is 44 years. The proportion of their ages after 8 years will be",
        "answer" : "8:7"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ten years ago A was half of B in age. If the ratio of their present ages is 3 : 4, what will be the total of their present ages",
        "answer" : "35"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ratio of the ages of Mahesh and Nilesh is 5 : x. Mahesh is 18 years younger to Ramesh. After nine years Ramesh will be 47 years old. If the difference between the ages of Mahesh and Nilesh is same as the age of Ramesh, what is the value of x ?",
        "answer" : "14.5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Mother’s age today is thrice as her daughter’s. After 10 years it would be just double. How old is the daughter today ?",
        "answer" : "10 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio of the ages of Maala and Kala is 4 : 3. The total of their ages is 2.8 decades. The proportion of their ages after 0.8 decades will be [1 Decade = 10 years]",
        "answer" : "6:5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Raju got married 8years ago. His present age is 6/5 times his age at the time of his marriage  Raju's sister was 10years younger to him at the time of his marriage. The present age of Raju's sister is  ?",
        "answer" : "38"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Six years ago Anita was P times as old as Ben was. If Anita is now 17 years old, how old is Ben now in terms of P ?",
        "answer" : "11/P + 6"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The age of a person is thrice the total ages of his 2 daughters. 0.5 decades hence, his age will be twice of the total ages of his daughters. Then what is the father’s current age? [0.5 Decades = 5 Years]",
        "answer" : "45 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man's current age is 2/5 of the age of his father. After 8 years, he will be 1/2 of the age of his father. What is the age of father at now ?",
        "answer" : "40"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Sum of the ages of Rajesh, Suresh, Mahesh and Dinesh is 76 years. 7 years hence, their age ratio is 7:6:5:8. Find Mahesh’s present age ?",
        "answer" : "13 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Sachin is younger than Rahul by 7 years. If the ratio of their ages is 7:9, find the age of Sachin",
        "answer" : " 24.5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The average age of 80 boys in a class is 15. The average age of group of 15 boys in the class is 16 and the average of another 25 boys in the class is 14. What is the average age of the remaining boys in the class ?",
        "answer" : "15.25 yrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The Average age of 12 men is decreased by one year when two of them having ages 28 years and 32 years are replaced by two women of same age . The age of a women is?",
        "answer" : "24 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If Raj was one-third as old as Rahim 5 years back and Raj is 17 years old now, How old is Rahim now?",
        "answer" : "41"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man is 24 years older than his son. In two years, his age will be twice the age of his son. The present age of his son is",
        "answer" : "22"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Proportion of Yuvaraj’s age to Ganguly’s age is 4:3. Yuvaraj willl be 26 years old after 6 years. What is the age of Ganguly now ?",
        "answer" : "15 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ten years ago, Kumar was thrice as old as Sailesh was but 10 years hence, he will be only twice as old. Find Kumar’s present age ?",
        "answer" : "70 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If two times of the daughter’s age in years is included to the mother’s age, the total is 70 and if two times of the mother’s age is included to the daughter’s age, the total is 95. So the Mother’s age is,",
        "answer" : " 40"
    },
    {
        "question" : "0.1 decates ago, Vijaya was quadrice as old as her daughter Simran. 0.6 decades hence, Vijaya’s age will beat her daughter’s age by 0.9 decades. The proportion of the current ages of Vijaya and Simran is : [ 0.1 Decates =1 Year; quadrice = 4 times]",
        "answer" : "13;4"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A is three times as old as B. C was twice-as old as A four years ago. In four years' time, A will be 31. What are the present ages of B and C ?",
        "answer" : "9, 50"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The average age of A and B, 2 years ago was 26. If the age of A, 5 years hence is 40 yrs, and B is 5 years younger to C, then find the difference between the age of A and C?",
        "answer" : "9 yrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "When Ram was born, his father was 32 years older than his brother and his mother was 25 years older than his sister. If Ram's brother is 6 years older than Ram and his mother is 3 years younger than his father, how old was Ram's sister when Ram was born ?",
        "answer" : "10 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The sum of the ages of 5 children born at the intervals of 3 years each is 50 years. what is the age of the youngest child ?",
        "answer" : "4"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ages of Anushka, Kajal and Charu latha together are 57 years. Bharti is thrice as old as Anushka and Charu latha is 12 years older than Anushka. Then, the respective age of Anushka, Kajal and Charu latha is ?",
        "answer" : "9, 27, 21"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Today is Varun's birthday. One year, from today he will be twice as old as he was 12 years ago. How old is Varun today ?",
        "answer" : "25 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ten years ago, Karan was thrice as old as Shiva was but 10 years hence, he will be only twice as old. Find Shiva’s present age ?",
        "answer" : "30 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The average age of a couple is 24 years when they were married five years ago but now the average age of the husband, wife and child is 20 years(the child was born during the interval). What is the present age of the child ?",
        "answer" : "2 yrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The age of Sohail, Afzal and Bilal are 17,16 and 12 respectively. If the age of Aslam also included the average of the ages is increased by 5. What is the age of Aslam?",
        "answer" : "35"
    },
    {
        "question" : "At present, the ratio between the ages of Arun and Harish is 4:3. After 6 years, Arun's age will be 26 years. What is the age of Harish at present ?",
        "answer" : "15 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "8 years ago Rama's mother was five times older than her daughter. After 8 years the mother will be twice older than her daughter . Find the present age of Rama?",
        "answer" : "40/3 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "When Raj Tarun was born, his father was 32 years older than his brother and his mother was 25 years older than his sister. If Raj Tarun's brother is 6 years older than Raj Tarun and his mother is 3 years younger than his father, how old was Raj Tarun's sister when Raj Tarun was born ?",
        "answer" : "10"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Rajan's present age is three times his daughter's and nine-thirteenth of his mother's present age. The sum of the present ages of all three of them is 125 years. What is the difference between the present ages of Rajan's daughter and Rajan's mather ?",
        "answer" : "50 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A is two years older than B who is twice as old as C. If the total of the ages of A, B and C be 27, then how old is B ?",
        "answer" : "10 yrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Anu's present age is 9 years more than that of what Raj's age will be after five years. Raj's present age is seven years more than that of what Renu's age was 4 years ago. Renu's present age is 19 years. What will be Anu's age after 5 years ?",
        "answer" : "41 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If Riya's age is four times the age of Siya and if Riya's age is 24 yrs , find the age difference between Riya and Siya ? ",
        "answer" : "18 yrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Hari Ram’s present age is three times his son’s present age and two fifth of his father’s present age. The average of the present age of all of them is 46 years. What is the difference between Hari Ram’s son’s present age and Hari Ram’s father’s present age? ",
        "answer" : "78 yrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The average age of a couple was 26 years at the time of marriage. After 11 years of marriage, the average age of the family with 3 children become 19 years. The average age of the children is",
        "answer" : "7 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio of Karthik’s and Kalyan’s ages is 4: 5. If the difference between the present age of Kalyan and the age of Karthik 5 years hence is 3 years, then what is the total of present ages of Karthik and Kalyan?",
        "answer" : " 72 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The average of the ages of Sumit, Krishna and Rishabh is 43 years and the average of the ages of Sumit, Rishabh and Rohit is 49 years. If Rohit is 54 years old, what is Krishna'a age ? ",
        "answer" : "36 yrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A woman says, 'If you reverse my own age, the figures represent my husband's age. He is, of course, senior to me and the difference between our ages is one-eleventh of their sum.' The woman's husband age is ?",
        "answer" : "54"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Sony is one-fifth the age of her mother 15 years ago and Sony’s brother is three-fifth the age of his mother 10 years ago. If the sum of Sony and her brother’s ages is 31 then how old is Sony's mother ? ",
        "answer" : "50"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Avanthi’s age is 1/6th of her father’s age. Her father’s age will be twice of Kapil’s age after 10 years. If Kapil’s eighth birthday was celebrated two years ago, then what is Avanthi’s present age ?",
        "answer" : "5 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man said to his son, 'I was two-thirds of your present age when you were born'. IIf the present age of the man is 48 years, find the present age of the son",
        "answer" : "28.8 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Average age of 4 daughters of a family is 12 years. The average age of daughters and their parents is 26 years. If the mother is 4 years older than the father, then what is the age (in years) of the father?",
        "answer" : "52"
    },
    {
        "question" : "One-third of Poojitha's age three years ago plus one-half of her age two years from now is twenty years. How old is she now?",
        "answer" : "24 yrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "John is 15 years younger than Jill, 12 years ago, Jill's age was 1.5 times that of John. Jill is now ___ years old",
        "answer" : "57"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The difference between the ages of mother and son was 21 when mother's age was 43. If father is elder by 3 years to mother, what will be the difference between the ages of son and father when father attains 50 years?",
        "answer" : "24"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A year ago Akash's father's age was 9 times that of Akash. After 3 years his father's age will be 5 times hat of his age. How old will Akash be next year?",
        "answer" : "6 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Monica's father was 38 years of age when she was born while her mother was 36 years old when her sister four years younger to her was born. What is the difference between the ages of her parents?",
        "answer" : "6 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Average age of 4 daughters of a family is 12 years. The average age of daughters and their parents is 26 years. If the mother is 4 years older than the father, then what is the age (in years) of the father?",
        "answer" : "52"
    },
    {
        "question" : "One-third of Poojitha's age three years ago plus one-half of her age two years from now is twenty years. How old is she now?",
        "answer" : "24 yrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Present age of R and S are in the ratio of 3 : 2 respectively. If the present age of H is 117 years and R’s present age is 4/13 of H’s present age, then after how many years the ages of R and S would be in the ratio of 15 : 11?",
        "answer" : "9"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Average age of 5 students of a school is 14 years. The average age of students and their Mathematics and science teachers is 30 years. If the age of science teacher is 6 years more than the age of Mathematics teacher, then what is the age (in years) of Mathematics teacher?",
        "answer" : "67"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What is the age of the eldest sister if, the sum of ages of 5 sisters born at the intervals of 3 years each is 50 years?",
        "answer" : "16 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Tom's father is thrice as old as Tom. 10 years ago Tom's father's age was 7 times his age. What is Tom's current age?",
        "answer" : "14 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Present age of Ashok is twice the present age of Kishan. After 7 years the Kishan’s age will be 4 times of the Kartik’s present age. If Kartik celebrated his 9thbirthday 3 years ago, then what will be the present age (in years) of Ashok?",
        "answer" : "82"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Today is Monday. After 68 days, it will be:",
        "answer" : "Saturday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The last day of a century cannot be:",
        "answer" : "Thursday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What day on 23.04.1990?",
        "answer" : "Monday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What day of week was it on 1989/05/11, if it was Monday on 1988/04/04, given the dates are in format : yyyy/dd/mm ?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If 01/04/2013 is Monday, then what is the day on 30/11/2013?",
        "answer" : "we can compare it with 29/04/2013, as it also had monday on that day find the remainder with number of days%7 number of days in april =30-29 =1 number of days in may =31 %7 =3 number of days in june =30 %7 =2 number of days in july =31 %7 =3 number of days in august =31 %7 =3 number of days in september =30 %7 =2 number of days in october =31 %7 =3 number of days in november =30 %7 =2 total count=1+3+2+3+3+2+3+2 = 19 %7 =5 Now we add 5 days in monday then it will be saturday. "
    },
    {
        "question" : "If January 1, 2016 was a Friday, what day of the week will be on January 1, 2017?",
        "answer" : "The year 2016 is the leap year which has 366 days i.e. 52 weeks and 2 more days. After each week, the day starts repetition. So the day on January 1, 2017 will be 2 days beyond Friday. That is Sunday."
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day of the week on January 30, 1948?",
        "answer" : "Friday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day of the week on January 1, 2001?",
        "answer" : "Monday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "It was Sunday on Jan 1, 2006. What was the day of the week Jan 1, 2010?",
        "answer" : "On 31st December, 2005 it was Saturday.vNumber of odd days from the year 2006 to the year 2009 = (1 + 1 + 2 + 1) = 5 days. On 31st December 2009, it was Thursday. Thus, on 1st Jan, 2010 it is Friday."
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day of the week on 28th May, 2006?",
        "answer" : "Given day is Sunday."
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day of the week on 17th June, 1998?",
        "answer" : "Wednesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What will be the day of the week 15th August, 2010?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Today is Monday. After 61 days, it will be:",
        "answer" : "Saturday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If 6th March, 2005 is Monday, what was the day of the week on 6th March, 2004?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "On what dates of April, 2001 did Wednesday fall?",
        "answer" : "4th, 11th, 18th, 25th"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The last day of a century cannot be",
        "answer" : "Tuesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "On 8th Feb, 2005 it was Tuesday. What was the day of the week on 8th Feb, 2004?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "On 8th Dec, 2007 Saturday falls. What day of the week was it on 8th Dec, 2006?",
        "answer" : "Friday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "January 1, 2008 is Tuesday. What day of the week lies on Jan 1, 2009?",
        "answer" : "Thursday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "January 1, 2007 was Monday. What day of the week lies on Jan. 1, 2008?",
        "answer" : "Tuesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day on 15th august 1947 ?",
        "answer" : "Friday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Today is Monday. After 61 days, it will be :",
        "answer" : " Saturday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "It was Sunday on Jan 1, 2006. What was the day of the week Jan 1, 2010?",
        "answer" : "Friday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The last day of a century cannot be",
        "answer" : "Tuesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day of the week on 28th May, 2006?",
        "answer" : " Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day of the week on, 16th July, 1776?",
        "answer" : "Tuesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What will be the day of the week 15th August, 2010?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many weekends in a year?",
        "answer" : "52"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day of the week on 17th June, 1998 ?",
        "answer" : "Wednesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If 6th March, 2005 is Monday, what was the day of the week on 6th March, 2004?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "On what dates of April, 2001 did Wednesday fall?",
        "answer" : "4th,11th,18th,25th"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many days are there in x weeks x days?",
        "answer" : "x weeks x days = (7x + x) days = 8x days."
    },
    {
        "question" : "26 january 1950 which day of the week? A) Monday B) Wednesday C) Thursday D) Tuesday",
        "answer" : "Thursday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many leap years does 100 years have?",
        "answer" : "24"
    },
    {
        "question" : "On 8th Dec, 2007 Saturday falls. What day of the week was it on 8th Dec, 2006?",
        "answer" : "Friday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Which two months in a year have the same calendar?",
        "answer" : "April, July"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What is 90 days from today? Hints : Today is 20th January 2017, Sunday",
        "answer" : "20th April, Saturday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "January 1, 2007 was Monday. What day of the week lies on Jan. 1, 2008?",
        "answer" : "Tuesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "On 8th Feb, 2005 it was Tuesday. What was the day of the week on 8th Feb, 2004?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The maximum gap between two successive leap year is?",
        "answer" : "8"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many leap years do 300 years have?",
        "answer" : "72"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If today is Saturday, what will be the day 350 days from now  ?",
        "answer" : "Saturday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The calendar of the year 1897 can be used again in the year? A) 1908 B) 1901 C) 1903 D) 1926",
        "answer" : "1903"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The year next to 2005 will have the same calendar as that of the year 2005? A) 2016  B) 2022 C) 2011 D) None",
        "answer" : "C) 2011"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The second day of a month is Sunday, What will be the last day of the next month which has 31 days  ?",
        "answer" : "Can't be determined"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The calendar for the year 1993 will be same for the year",
        "answer" : "1999"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The calendar for the year 2007 will be the same for the year",
        "answer" : "2018"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The calendar for the year 2018 will be the same for the year",
        "answer" : "2029"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The day before yesterday, I was 25 years old, and next year I will turn 28. How is it possible?",
        "answer" : "The day before yesterday(30 December 2016), I was 25 years old and next year(31 December 2018) I will be 28."
    },
    {
        "question" : "On what dates of July.2004 did Monday fall?",
        "answer" : "5th, 12th, 19th, 26th"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Prove that any date in March of a year is the same day of the week corresponding date in November that year.",
        "answer" : "Same day"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If Aug 15th,2012 falls on Thursday then June 11th,2013 falls on which day ?",
        "answer" : "Wednesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If Feb 12th,1986 falls on Wednesday then Jan 1st,1987 falls on which day?",
        "answer" : "Thursday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If Mar 18th,1994 falls on Friday then Feb 25th,1995 falls on which day?",
        "answer" : "Saturday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The calendar of the year 2024 can be used again in the year?",
        "answer" : "2052"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day of the week on 16th August, 1947?",
        "answer" : "Saturday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If every seconds Saturday and all Sundays are holidays in a 30 days month beginning on Saturday, then how many working days are there in that month ? (Month starts from Saturday)",
        "answer" : "23"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The calendar for the year 1988 is same as which upcoming year ?",
        "answer" : "2016"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The year next to 2003 will have the same calendar as that of the year 2003?",
        "answer" : "2014"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If July 9th,2013 falls on Sunday then Jan 7th,2014 falls on which day?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Given that on 9th August 2016 is Saturday. What was the day on 9th August 1616 ?",
        "answer" : "Saturday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Which year has 366 days?",
        "answer" : "1200"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If yesterday were tomorrow, then today would be Friday. What day is today?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "1.12.91 is the first Sunday. Which is the fourth Tuesday of December 91 ?",
        "answer" : "24.12.91"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Second & fourth Saturdays and every Sunday is a holiday. How many working days will be there in a month of 31 days beginning on a Friday ?",
        "answer" : "24"
    },
    {
        "question" : "On 17th March, 1997 Monday falls. What day of the week was it on 17th March, 1996?",
        "answer" : "Saturday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Suppose today is Friday, what day of the week will it be 65 days from now?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If 5th March, 2005 is Monday, what was the day of the week on 5th March, 2004 ?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The calendar of year 1989 was same as which year?",
        "answer" : "1978"
    },
    {
        "question" : "On 24th Nov, 2007 Thursday falls. What day of the week was it on 10th Nov, 2006 ?",
        "answer" : "Wednesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day of the week on 28th May, 2006?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many seconds in 10 years?",
        "answer" : "315360000 sec"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The calendar of year 1939 is same as which year?",
        "answer" : "1950"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day on 2nd Jan 1901 ?",
        "answer" : "Wednesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "On what dates of April, 2001 did Wednesday fall ?",
        "answer" : " 4th, 11th, 18th, 25th"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Oct 1st 1994 falls on which day?",
        "answer" : "Saturday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "It was Sunday on Jan 1, 2006. What was the day of the week Jan 1, 2010 ?",
        "answer" : "Friday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "On 19th June, 1984 Monday falls. What day of the week was it on 19th June, 1985?",
        "answer" : "Tuesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many days are there in k weeks k days ?",
        "answer" : "k weeks k days = (7k + k) days = 8k days."
    },
    {
        "question" : "What will be the day of the week 15th August, 2010?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Aizaz was born on 5th January 2015, while Faiz was born 553days later. On which date was Faiz born?",
        "answer" : "11th July 2016"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If 4th december 1999 is Monday then what day is 3rd january 2000 ?",
        "answer" : "Wednesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What is two weeks from today? A) same day B) previous day C) next day D) None",
        "answer" : "same day"
    },
    {
        "question" : "On 1st Jan, 2005 Saturday falls. What day of the week was it on 1st Jan, 2006?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day on 16th June,1993?",
        "answer" : "Wednesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Which century year is a leap year? A) 1900 B) 1700 C) 1600 D) 1100",
        "answer" : "C)  1600"
    },
    {
        "question" : "1.12.91 is the first Tuesday. Which is the fourth Thursday of December 91  ?",
        "answer" : "25.12.91"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What day would it be on 1 September 2020?",
        "answer" : "Tuesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How old are you if you are born in 1995? Considering present year as 2018",
        "answer" : "23"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The calendar of the year 2006 was used before in the year? A) 1990 B) 1995 C) 2002 D) 2000",
        "answer" : "B) 1995"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a year, Holi was enjoyed on 6th March 9 AM and Deepawali was celebrated on 11th November 8 PM. The total time interval (in hours) between the two was ?",
        "answer" : "6011 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day on 31st Dec,2011 ?",
        "answer" : "Saturday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "On 8th Dec, 2007 Saturday falls. What day of the week was it on 8th Dec, 2006 ?",
        "answer" : "Friday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many days in 4 years?",
        "answer" : "1460"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The calendar for the year 2013 was the same as the year :",
        "answer" : "2002"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The calendar of year 1856 is same as which year?",
        "answer" : "1884"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day on 9th May,2001?",
        "answer" : "Wednesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Which calendar was used again in the year 1856?",
        "answer" : "1828"
    },
    {
        "question" : "It was Sunday on Jan 1, 2006. What was the day of the week Jan 1, 2010?",
        "answer" : "Friday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day of the week on 28th May, 2006?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Which of the following years have 366 days?",
        "answer" : "1984"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What will be the day on 18th Feb,2016?",
        "answer" : "Thursday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The last day of a century cannot be",
        "answer" : "Tuesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What day would it be on 1 september 2020 ?",
        "answer" : "Tuesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How much does a clock lose per day, if its hands coincide ever 65 minutes ?",
        "answer" : "1425/18 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "April 19th, 1986 falls on which day?",
        "answer" : "Saturday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "On 8th Feb, 2005 it was Tuesday. What was the day of the week on 8th Feb, 2004?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If 6th March, 2005 is Monday, what was the day of the week on 6th March, 2004?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day on 25th Jan,1981?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "From the following years,which is not a leap year ?",
        "answer" : "1863"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What was the day of the week on 17th June, 1998?",
        "answer" : "Wednesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Which year will have the same calendar as that of 2005? A) 2009 B) 2010 C) 2011 D) 2008" ,
        "answer" : "2011"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Which of the following year is a leap year? A) 2500 B) 1700 C) 1900 D) 2400",
        "answer" : "2400"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If 6th March, 2005 is Monday, what was the day of the week on 6th March, 2004?",
        "answer" : "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "It was Sunday on Jan 1, 2006. What was the day of the week Jan 1, 2010?",
        "answer" : "Friday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What day of the week was 29 June 2010 ?",
        "answer" : "Tuesday"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The calendar for the year 2007 will be the same for the year ?",
        "answer" : "2018"
    },
    {
        "question" : "5th January 2018 was a Friday. Which of the following years will also have 5th January on a Friday?",
        "answer" : "2024"
    },
    {
        "question" : "There are two types of sugar. One is priced at Rs 62 per kg and the other is priced at Rs 72 per kg. If the two types are mixed together, the price of new mixture will be Rs 64.50 per kg. Find the ratio of the two types of sugar in this new mixture.",
        "answer" : "3:1"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A certain quantity of water is mixed with milk priced at Rs 12 per litre. The price of mixture is Rs 8 per litre. Find out the ratio of water and milk in the new mixture.",
        "answer" : "1:2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A drum contains forty liters of whisky. Four liters of whisky is taken out and replaced by soda. This process is carried out twice further. How much whisky is now contained by the container?",
        "answer" : "29.16 Lt"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Rice of rate Rs. 126 per kg and Rs. 135 per kg and 3rd variety in the ratio 1 : 1 : 2. If the final mixture is worth Rs. 153 per kg, what is the rate of the third variety per kg?",
        "answer" : "175.5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sikanji vendor has two drums of sikanji. The first contains 75% of sikanji. The second contains 50% sikanji. How much sikanji should he mix from each of the drum so as to get twelve litres of sikanji such that the ratio of sikanji to soda is 5 : 3?",
        "answer" : "6"
    },
    {
        "question" : "There are two drums of vanaspati gee. One of them contains 25% of oil (and rest 75% gee) and the another contains 50% oil (and rest 50% gee). How much vanaspati gee (approx) should one mix from each of the drum so as to get 14 litres of vanaspati gee such that the ratio of gee to oil is 5 : 2?",
        "answer" : "12 , 2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two solutions S1 and S2 contain whisky and soda in the ratio 2 : 5 and 6 : 7 respectively. In what ratio these solutions be mixed to get a new solution S3,  containing whisky and soda in the ratio 5 : 8 ?",
        "answer" : "7 : 9"
    },
    {
        "question" : "8 liters of wine is replaced by water from a pot full of wine and repeated this two more times. The ratio of the wine:total left in pot is 8 : 27. How much wine was there in the pot originally?",
        "answer" : "24"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A vessel full of orange juice contains 40% orange pulp. A part of juice is replaced by another juice containing 19% orange pulp and now the percentage of orange pulp is found to be 26%. What quantity of juice is replaced?",
        "answer" : "2:3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many kg of rice, of cost 9 Rs/kg must be mixed with 27 kg of rice of cost 7 Rs/kg get a gain of 10 % by selling the mixture at 9.24 Rs/kg?",
        "answer" : "63"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio should a kind of sugar at 8.70 Rs/kg be mixed with another kind of sugar at 9.70 Rs/kg so that the mixture be worth 9 Rs/kg?",
        "answer" : "7:3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio must rice of one kind worth Rs. 50/kg be mixed with another kind of rice of worth Rs. 55/kg such that by selling the mixture at Rs. 57.20/kg, there can be a gain 10%?",
        "answer" : "3:2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A drum filled with a mixture of two liquids l1 and l2 in the ratio 5:7. When 9 liters of mixture is taken out and the replaced by l1. Now the ratio of l1 and l2 is 9:7. How many liters of the liquid l1 were there in the drum initially?",
        "answer" : "15"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio a vendor should mix rice at Rs.60 per kg with rice at Rs. 68 per kg so that the final rice mixture must be of worth Rs. 63 per kg?",
        "answer" : "3:1"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A vessel is filled with a solution of, 3 parts soda and 5 parts rum. How much of the solution must be taken out and replaced with soda so that the solution contains equal amount of sod and rum?",
        "answer" : "1/5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A grocer wishes to sell a mixture of two variety of pulses worth Rs.16 per kg. In what ratio must he mix the pulses to reach this selling price, when cost of one variety of pulses is Rs.14 per kg and the other is Rs.24 per kg?",
        "answer" : "4:1"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Cost of two types of pulses is Rs.15 and Rs, 20 per kg, respectively. If both the pulses are mixed together in the ratio 2:3, then what should be the price of mixed variety of pulses per kg?",
        "answer" : "Rs. 18 per Kg"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A dealer has 1000 kg sugar and he sells a part of it at 8% profit and the rest of it at 18% profit. The overall profit he earns is 14%. What is the quantity which is sold at 18% profit?",
        "answer" : "60 Kg"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How much coffee of variety A, costing Rs. 5 a kg should be added to 20 kg of Type B coffee at Rs. 12 a kg so that the cost of the two coffee variety mixture be worth Rs. 7 a kg?",
        "answer" : "50 Kg"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A vessel is filled with liquid, 3 parts of which are water and 5 parts syrup. How much of the mixture must be drawn off and replaced with water so that the mixture may be half water and half syrup?",
        "answer" : "1/5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Tea worth Rs. 126 per kg and Rs. 135 per kg are mixed with a third variety in the ratio 1 : 1 : 2. If the mixture is worth Rs. 153 per kg, the price of the third variety per kg will be:",
        "answer" : "Rs. 175.50"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A can contains a mixture of two liquids A and B is the ratio 7 : 5. When 9 litres of mixture are drawn off and the can is filled with B, the ratio of A and B becomes 7 : 9. How many litres of liquid A was contained by the can initially?",
        "answer" : "21"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A milk vendor has 2 cans of milk. The first contains 25% water and the rest milk. The second contains 50% water. How much milk should he mix from each of the containers so as to get 12 litres of milk such that the ratio of water to milk is 3 : 5?",
        "answer" : "6 litres, 6 litres"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio must a grocer mix two varieties of pulses costing Rs. 15 and Rs. 20 per kg respectively so as to get a mixture worth Rs. 16.50 kg?",
        "answer" : "7:3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A dishonest milkman professes to sell his milk at cost price but he mixes it with water and thereby gains 25%. The percentage of water in the mixture is:",
        "answer" : "20%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many kilogram of sugar costing Rs. 9 per kg must be mixed with 27 kg of sugar costing Rs. 7 per kg so that there may be a gain of 10% by selling the mixture at Rs. 9.24 per kg?",
        "answer" : "63 Kg"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A container contains 40 litres of milk. From this container 4 litres of milk was taken out and replaced by water. This process was repeated further two times. How much milk is now contained by the container?",
        "answer" : "29.16 litres"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A jar full of whisky contains 40% alcohol. A part of this whisky is replaced by another containing 19% alcohol and now the percentage of alcohol was found to be 26%. The quantity of whisky replaced is:",
        "answer" : "2/3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio must water be mixed with milk to gain 16% on selling the mixture at cost price?",
        "answer" : "1:6"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Find the ratio in which rice at Rs. 7.20 a kg be mixed with rice at Rs. 5.70 a kg to produce a mixture worth Rs. 6.30 a kg.",
        "answer" : "2:3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio must a grocer mix two varieties of tea worth Rs. 60 a kg and Rs. 65 a kg so that by selling the mixture at Rs. 68.20 a kg he may gain 10%?",
        "answer" : "3:2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The cost of Type 1 rice is Rs. 15 per kg and Type 2 rice is Rs. 20 per kg. If both Type 1 and Type 2 are mixed in the ratio of 2 : 3, then the price per kg of the mixed variety of rice is:",
        "answer" : "Rs. 18"
    },
    {
        "question" : "8 litres are drawn from a cask full of wine and is then filled with water. This operation is performed three more times. The ratio of the quantity of wine now left in cask to that of water is 16 : 65. How much wine did the cask hold originally?",
        "answer" : "24 litres"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A merchant has 1000 kg of sugar, part of which he sells at 8% profit and the rest at 18% profit. He gains 14% on the whole. The quantity sold at 18% profit is:",
        "answer" : "600 Kg"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A vessel contains a mixture of P and Q in the ratio of 5 : 3. 16 liters of this mixture is taken out and 5 liters of P is poured in. The new mixture has a ratio of P to Q as 11 : 6. Find the total original quantity of mixture.",
        "answer" : "96 liters"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio of milk and water in a solution is 20 : 7 and after adding 5 liters of water in it the ratio of milk and water becomes 5 : 3, then find the final amount of water in the final solution.",
        "answer" : "12 litres."
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two vessels of equal capacity contain juice and water in the ratio of 7 : 2 and 11 : 7 respectively. The mixture of both vessels is mixed and transferred into a bigger vessel. What is the ratio of juice and water in the new mixture?",
        "answer" : "25 : 11"
    },
    {
        "question" : " A butler stole wine from a butt of Rony which contained 40% of spirit and he replaced what he had stolen with wine containing only 16% spirit. The butt was then 24% strength only. How much of the butt did he steal?",
        "answer" : "2/3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A shopkeeper mixed low-quality vegetable oil costing Rs. 40 per litre with sunflower refined oil costing Rs. 80 per litre in a ratio of 2 ∶ 3 respectively. If he sold the mixture at Rs. 100 per litre, find his profit percentage.",
        "answer" : "56.25%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A bucket contains 64 liters of petrol. 16 liters of petrol is removed and replaced with kerosene. 16 liters of this mixture is removed and replaced with kerosene. How much kerosene (in liters) is present now?",
        "answer" : "28 liters"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A vessel is full of Petrol. 1/4th of the Petrol is taken out and replaced with kerosene oil. If the process is repeated 3 more times, 81 litres of Petrol is finally left in the vessel. Find the capacity of the vessel.",
        "answer" : "256 L"
    },
    {
        "question" : " 8L Cold drink was added to a 20L mixture of water and alcohol such that the ratio of alcohol to that of cold drink and water is 1 : 3. Find the amount of alcohol in the solution.",
        "answer" : "7L of alcohol is present in the mixture."
    },
    {
        "question" : "8 litres are drawn from a cask full of wine and is then filled with water. This operation is performed three more times. The ratio of the quantity of wine now left in cask to that of the water is 16 : 65. How much wine the cask hold originally?",
        "answer" : "24 litres"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A merchant has 1000 kg of sugar part of which he sells at 8% profit and the rest at 18% profit. He gains 14% on the whole. The Quantity sold at 18% profit is",
        "answer" : "600 kg"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Tea worth of Rs. 135/kg & Rs. 126/kg are mixed with a third variety in the ratio 1: 1 : 2. If the mixture is worth Rs. 153 per kg, the price of the third variety per kg will be",
        "answer" : "Rs. 175.50 "
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many kilograms of sugar costing Rs. 9 per kg must be mixed with 27 kg of sugar costing Rs. 7 per Kg so that there may be a gain of 10 % by selling the mixture at Rs. 9.24 per Kg ?",
        "answer" : "63 Kg"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The cost of Type 1 rice is Rs. 15 per kg and Type 2 rice is Rs.20 per kg. If both Type 1 and Type 2 are mixed in the ratio of 2 : 3, then the price per kg of the mixed variety of rice is",
        "answer" : "Rs. 18"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A can contains a mixture of two liquids A and B in the ratio  7 : 5. When 9 litres of mixture are drawn off and the can is filled with B, the ratio of A and B becomes 7 : 9. How many litres of liquid A was contained by the can initially?",
        "answer" : "21"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A mixture of 150 liters of wine and water contains 20% water. How much more water should be added so that water becomes 25% of the new mixture?",
        "answer" : "10 litres"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A vessel contains 20 liters of a mixture of milk and water in the ratio 3:2. 10 liters of the mixture are removed and replaced with an equal quantity of pure milk. If the process is repeated once more, find the ratio of milk and water in the final mixture obtained ?",
        "answer" : "9:1 "
    },
    {
        "question" : "Find the ratio in which rice at Rs. 7.20 a kg be mixed with rice at Rs. 5.70 a kg to produce a mixture worth Rs. 6.30 a kg.",
        "answer" : "2:3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A container contains 50 litres of milk. From that 8 litres of milk was taken out and replaced by water. This process was repeated further two times. How much milk is now contained by the container ?",
        "answer" : "29.63 litres "
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio of petrol and kerosene in the container is 3:2 when 10 liters of the mixture is taken out and is replaced by the kerosene, the ratio become 2:3. Then total quantity of the mixture in the container is:",
        "answer" : "30"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The diluted wine contains only 8 liters of wine and the rest is water. A new mixture whose concentration is 30%, is to be  formed by replacing wine. How many liters of mixture shall be replaced with pure wine if there was initially 32 liters of water in the mixture ?",
        "answer" : "5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio of expenditure and savings is 3 : 2 . If the income increases by 15% and the savings increases by 6% , then by how much percent should his expenditure increases?",
        "answer" : "21"
    },
    {
        "question" : "From a container, 6 liters milk was drawn out and was replaced by water. Again 6 liters of mixture was drawn out and was replaced by the water. Thus the quantity of milk and water in the container after these two operations is 9:16. The quantity of mixture is:",
        "answer" : "15"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A milk man sells the milk at the cost price but he mixes the water in it and thus he gains 9.09%. The quantity of water in the mixture of 1 liter is :",
        "answer" : "83.33 ml"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a mixture of milk and water the proportion of water by weight was 75%. If in 60 gm of mixture 15 gm water was added, what would be the percentage of water ? (Weight in gm)",
        "answer" : "80%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of Rs.118 was divided among 50 boys and girls such that each boy received Rs.2.60 and each girl Rs.1.80. Find the number of boys and girls ?",
        "answer": "15"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A jar was full with honey. A person  used to draw out 20% of the honey from the jar and replaced it with sugar solution. He has repeated  the same process 4 times and thus there was only 512 gm of honey left in the jar, the rest part of the jar was filled with the sugar  solution. The initial amount of honey in the jar was filled with the sugar solution. The initial amount of honey in the jar was:",
        "answer": "1.25 kg"
    },
    {
        "question" : "From  a container of wine, a thief has stolen 15 liters of wine and replaced it with same quantity of water.He again repeated the same process. Thus in three attempts the ratio of wine and water became 343:169. The  initial amount of wine in the container was:",
        "answer": "120 liters"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The average weight of boys in a class is 30 kg and the average weight of girls in the same class is 20kg. If the average weight of the whole class is 23.25 kg, what could be the possible strength of boys and girls respectively in the same class?",
        "answer": "13 and 27"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio of water and alcohol in two different containers is 2:3 and 4:5. In what ratio we are required to mix the mixtures  of two containers in order to get the new mixture in which the ratio of alcohol and water be 7:5?",
        "answer": "5:3 "
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a pot, there is a mixture of milk and water in the ratio 4 : 5. If it is filled with an additional 8 litres of milk, the pot would be full and ratio of milk and water would become 6 : 5. Find the capacity of the pot ?",
        "answer": "22 lit"
    },
    {
        "question" : "n the 75 litres of mixture of milk and water, the ratio of milk and water is 4:1. The quantity of water required to make the ratio of milk and water 3:1 is ",
        "answer": "5 litres"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a mixture of milk and water, there is only 26% water. After replacing the mixture with 7 liters of pure milk , the percentage of milk in the mixture  become 76%. The quantity of mixture is:",
        "answer": "91 litres"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A vessel is filled with liquid, 3 parts of which are water and 5 parts of syrup. How much of the mixture must be drawn off and replaced with water so that the mixture may be half water and half syrup?",
        "answer": "1/5 "
    },
    {
        "question" : "Equal quantities of three mixtures of milk and water are mixed in the ratio 1:2, 2:3 and 3:4. The ratio of water and milk in the mixture is ?",
        "answer": "193 : 122"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A mixture of 150 liters of wine and water contains 20% water. How much more water should be added so that water becomes 25% of the new mixture ?",
        "answer": "10 lit"
    },
    {
        "question" : "From a tank of petrol , which contains 200 liters of petrol, the seller replaces each time with kerosene when he sells 40 liters of petrol(or mixture). Everytime he sells out only 40 liters of petrol (pure or impure). After replacing the petrol with kerosene 4th time, the total amount of kerosene in the mixture is",
        "answer": "118.08L"
    },
    {
        "question" : " kg of a metal contains 1/5 copper and rest in Zinc. Another 5 kg of metal contains 1/6 copper and rest in Zinc.The ratio of Copper and Zinc  into the mixture of these two metals:",
        "answer": "49 : 221"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio should two varieties of sugar at Rs.18 per kg and Rs.24 Kg be mixed together to get a mixture whose cost is Rs.20 per kg ?",
        "answer" : "2 : 1"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A container contains 40 litres of milk.From this container 4 litres of milk was taken out and replaced by water. This process was repeated further two times. How much milk is now contained by the container.",
        "answer" : "29.16 litres"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man travelled a distance of 80 km in 7 hours partly on foot at the rate of 8 km per hour and partly on bicycle at 16 km /hr. Find the distance travelled on foot ?",
        "answer" : "32 km"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many liters of oil at Rs.40 per liter should be mixed with 240 liters of a second variety of oil at Rs.60 per liter so as to get a maximum whose cost is Rs.52 per liter ?",
        "answer" : "2:3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Milk and water are mixed in a vessel A as 4:1 and in vessel B as 3:2. For vessel C, if one takes equal quantities from A and B, find the ratio of milk to water in C.",
        "answer" : "7:3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "One type of liquid contains 25 % of benzene, the other contains 30% of benzene. A can is filled with 6 parts of the first liquid and 4 parts of the second liquid. Find the percentage of benzene in the new mixture.",
        "answer" : "27%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "From the 50 liters of milk, 5 liters of milk is taken out and after it 5 liters of water is added to the rest amount of milk. Again 5 liters of milk and water is drawn out and it was replaced by 5 liters of water. If this process is continued  similarly for the third time, the amount of milk left after the third replacement: ",
        "answer" : "36.45L"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The amount of water (in ml) that should be added to reduce 9 ml lotion, containing 50% alcohol, to a lotion containing 30% alcohol is ?",
        "answer" : "6 ml"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The milk and water in two vessels A and B are in the ratio 4:3 and 2:3 respectively. In what ratio the liquids in both the vessels be mixed to obtain a new mixture in vessel c consisting half milk and half water?",
        "answer" : "7:5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A milkman claims to sell milk at its cost price, still, he is making a profit of 30% since he has mixed some amount of water in the milk. What is the % of milk in the mixture?",
        "answer" : "76.92%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a 48 ltr mixture, the ratio of milk and water is 5:3. How much water should be added in the mixture so as the ratio will become 3:5 ?",
        "answer" : "32 lit"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A mixture of 70 litres of Fruit Juice and water contains 10% water. How many litres of water should be added to the mixture so that the mixture contains 12.5% water?",
        "answer" : "2 lit"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a 40 litre mixture of alcohol & water, the ratio of alcohol and water is 5 : 3. If 20% of this mixture is taken out and the same amount of water is added then what will be the ratio of alcohol and water in final mixture?",
        "answer" : "1:1"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How much pepsi at Rs.6 a litre is added to 15 litre of 'dew' at Rs. 10 a litre so that the price of the mixture be Rs.9 a litre?",
        "answer" : "5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio must wheat at Rs. 3.20/kg be mixed with wheat at Rs. 2.90/kg so that the mixture be worth Rs. 3/kg?",
        "answer" : "2:1"
    },
    {
        "question" : "There are two mixtures of honey and water in which the ratio of honey and water are as 1:3 and 3:1 respectively. Two litres are drawn from first mixture and 3 litres from second mixture, are mixed to form another mixture. What is the ratio of honey and water in it ?",
        "answer" : "11:9"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man pays Rs. 6.40 per litre of milk. He adds water and sells the mixture at Rs. 8 per litre, thereby making 37.5% profit. The proportion of water to milk received by the customers is",
        "answer" : "1:10"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If a man buys 1 lt of milk for Rs.12 and mixes it with 20% water and sells it for Rs.15, then what is the percentage of gain ?",
        "answer" : "25%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A tin a mixture of two liquids A and B in the proportion 4 : 1. If 45 litres of the mixture is replaced by 45 litres of liquid B, then the ratio of the two liquids becomes 2 : 5. How much of the liquid B was there in the tin? What quantity does the tin hold?",
        "answer" : "50 L"
    },
    {
        "question" : "From a tank of petrol, which contains 200 litres of petrol, the seller replaces each time with kerosene when he sells 40 litres of petrol(or its mixture). Everytime he sells out only 40 litres of petrol(pure or impure). After replacing the petrol with kerosen 4th time, the total amount of kerosene in the mixture is ",
        "answer" : "118.08L"
    },
    {
        "question" : "An alloy contains gold and silver in the ratio 5 : 8 and another alloy contains gold and silver in the ratio 5 : 3. If equal amount of both the alloys are melted together, then the ratio of gold and silver in the resulting alloy is ?",
        "answer" : "105/103"
    },
    {
        "question" : "From a container of wine, a thief has stolen 15 litres of wine and replaced it with same quantity of water. He again repeated the same process. Thus, in three attempts the ratio of wine and water became 343 : 169. The initial amount of wine in the container was:",
        "answer" : "120 Litres"
    },
    {
        "question" : "640 ml of a mixture contains milk and water in ratio 6:2. How much of the water is to be added to get a new mixture containing half milk and half water ?",
        "answer" : "320 ml"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a mixture, the ratio of juice and water is 4 : 3. By adding 6 litre water the ratio of juice and water will be 8 : 7. What is the amount of juice in the original mixture ?",
        "answer" : "48 lit"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio should two varieties of tea at Rs. 60 per kg and Rs.120 per kg be mixed together so that by selling the mixture at Rs.96 per kg, a profit of Rs.20% is obtained ?",
        "answer" : "2:1"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A jar was full with honey. A person used to draw out 20% of the honey from the jar and replaced it with sugar solution. He has repeated the same process 4 times and thus there was only 512 gm of honey left in the jar, the rest part of the jar was filled with the sugar solution. The initial amount of honey in the jar was:",
        "answer" : "1.25 Kg"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two bottles contains mixture of milk and water. First bottle contains 64% milk and second bottle contains 26% water. In what ratio these two mixtures are mixed so that new mixture contains 68% milk?",
        "answer" : "3 : 2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ratio of water and milk in a container is 2 : 3. If 40 liter mixture removed from the container and same quantity of milk is added to it then the ratio of water to milk becomes 1 : 4. Find the initial quantity of mixture ?",
        "answer" : "80 lit"
    },
    {
        "question" : "An alloy of copper and bronze weight 50g. It contains 80% Copper. How much copper should be added to the alloy so that percentage of copper is increased to 90%?",
        "answer" : "50 gm"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The concentration of glucose in three different mixtures (glucose and alcohol) is 12,35 and 45 respectively. If 2 litres, 3 litres and 1 litre are taken from these three different vessels and mixed. What is the ratio of glucose and alcohol in the new mixture?",
        "answer" : "3:2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A mixture contains 25% milk and rest water. What percent of this mixture must taken out and replaced with milk so that in mixture milk and water may become equal. ",
        "answer" : "33.33%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a mixture of 240 lt. water is 20% and rest is Milk. What quantity of mixture should be taken out and replaced with water so that water becomes 40%?",
        "answer" : "60 lit"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a 100 litre of mixture the ratio of milk and water is 6:4. How much milk must be added to the mixture in order to make the ratio 3 : 1?",
        "answer" : "60"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio must a merchant mix two varieties of oils worth Rs. 60/kg and Rs. 65/kg, so that by selling the mixture at Rs. 68.20/kg, he may gain 10% ?",
        "answer" : "3:2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio salt costing Rs 13/kg mixed with another salt costing Rs 7/ kg to get a mixture costing Rs 9/kg?",
        "answer" : "1:2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "7 litres mixture of milk and water contains 30% water. 3.5 litres of milk is added to this mixture. What is the percentage of water in the new mixture?",
        "answer" : "20"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In an amalgam, mercury and silver are in the ratio of 3 : 7. In the second amalgam, the ratio of same elements is 1 : 9. If equal quantities of these two amalgam are mixed to form a new amalgam, then what will be the ratio of both of these elements in the new amalgam?",
        "answer" : "1:4"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a mixture of 35 litres, the ratio of water and acid is 6 : 1. If 5 litres of acid is added to the mixture, then what will be the ratio of water and acid in the new  mixture?",
        "answer" : "3:1"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A mixture of 240 litres of juice and water contains 15% water. How much more water (in litres) should be added to this so that the strength of water will become 25% in the new mixture?",
        "answer" : "32"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A natural number, when divided by 5,6,7 or 8,leaves a remainder of 4 in each case. what is the smallest of all such numbers?",
        "answer" : "844"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Abdul prepared 42 lts of medicine and filled it in bottles of 280 ml each. Find how many bottles would be required?",
        "answer" : "150"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio must a mixture of 15% spirit strength be mixed with that of 25% spirit strength to get a mixture of 21% spirit strength?",
        "answer" : "2:3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two water-squash mixtures, the first having a water-to-squash ratio of 4 : 1 and the other having a ratio of 3 : 1, are blended in the ratio 1 : 2. What is the water : squash ratio in the blend?",
        "answer" : "23:7"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a mixture of 45 litres, the ratio of liquid A and liquid B is 7 : 2. If 11 litres of liquid B is added to the mixture, then what will be the ratio of liquid A and liquid B in the new mixture?",
        "answer" : "5:3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a mixture 25 liters, the ratio of milk and water is 4:1. How many liters of milk must be added to make the ratio 16:1?",
        "answer" : "60"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a bucket, paint and oil are in the ratio 7 : 5. 24 litres of mixture is drawn off and 24 litres of oil is added. If the ratio of paint and oil becomes 1 : 1, then how many litres of paint was contained in the bucket initially?",
        "answer" : "98"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio rice costing Rs 14/kg mixed with another rice costing Rs 11/kg to get the mixture costing Rs 11.6/kg?",
        "answer" : "1:5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio wheat costing Rs 17/kg mixed with another wheat costing Rs 12/kg to get a mixture costing Rs 13.5/ kg?",
        "answer" : "3:7"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A mixture contains liquid A and liquid B in the ratio of 5 : 4. If 2 litres of liquid B is added to it, then the ratio of liquid A and liquid B becomes 7 : 6. What is the quantity (in litres) of liquid A in the mixture?",
        "answer" : "35"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio of spirit and water in the two vessels is 5 : 1 and 3 : 7 respectively. In what ratio the liquid of both the vessels should be mixed such that a new mixture containing half spirit and half water is obtained?",
        "answer" : "3:5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Vipin adds 3 litres of liquid A in 6 litres of liquid B and Mohit adds 8 litres of liquid A in 15 litres of liquid B. What is the ratio of the percentage of liquid B in the two mixtures?",
        "answer" : "46:45"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a mixture of 165 litres, the ratio of liquids X and Y is 6 : 5. If 5 litres of liquid Y is added in the mixture, then what is the ratio of X and Y in the new mixture?",
        "answer" : "9:8"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio must a mixture of 11% sugar strength be mixed with that of 25% sugar strength so as to get a new mixture of 13% sugar strength?",
        "answer" : "6:1"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two water squash mixtures, the first with a water-to-squash ratio of 5:1 and the letter with a ratio of 3:1 are blended in the ratio 3:2. What is the final water : squash ratio in the blend?",
        "answer" : "4:1"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio of sand to gravel in a mixture is 17 : 9 while that between gravel and cement is 6 : 17. What is the ratio of sand to cement in the mixture?",
        "answer" : "2:3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two vessels of equal volume contain milk and water in the ratio 1:3 and 2:1. If they are mixed together, what is the new ratio?",
        "answer" : "11:13"
    },
    {
        "question" : "35% of an alloy was silver. If in the quantity of alloy there was 119 g of silver, what was the quantity of the elements in the alloy?",
        "answer" : "221g"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Rahul adds 2 litres of alcohol in 6 litres of water and Dinesh adds 1 litres of alcohol in 9 litres of water. What is the ratio of the percentage of alcohol in the two mixtures?",
        "answer" : "5:2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a mixture, ink and water are in the ratio of 8 : 5. If 24 litres of water is added to the mixture, then the new ratio becomes 8 : 11. What is the total quantity (in litres) of water in the new mixture?",
        "answer" : "44"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A mixture contains acid and water in the ratio of 7 : 3. If 4 litres of water is added to it, then the ratio of acid and water becomes 7 : 4. What is the quantity (in litres) of acid in the mixture?",
        "answer" : "28"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A mixture of alcohol and water contains 7% alcohol. How much mixture (in litres) is required to get 357 litres of alcohol?",
        "answer" : "5100"
    },
    {
        "question" : "25 litres of a mixture contains 30% of spirit and rest water. If 5 litres of water be mixed in it, the percentage of spirit in the new mixture is",
        "answer" : "25%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two vessels of equal capacity contains juice and water in the ratio of 5 : 1 and 5 : 7 respectively. The mixture of both the vessels are mixed and transferred into a bigger vessel. What is the ratio of juice and water in the new mixture?",
        "answer" : "5:3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A shop keeper purchased 15 kg of sugar and 20 kg of wheat at Rs. 50 and Rs. 75 per kg respectively. On selling them, he gained 10% on sugar and 20% on wheat. What was the total sale vale?",
        "answer" : "Rs. 2625"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ramesh uses a weight of 930 gm instead of 1 kg and sells sugar on its cost price. What will be his profit percentage on selling 15 kg sugar?",
        "answer" : "7.53"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a mixture, sugar and milk are in the ratio 4 : 5. If 7 litres of milk is added to it, then the ratio of sugar and milk in the new mixture becomes 2 : 3. What is the total quantity (In litres) of sugar in new mixture?",
        "answer" : "28"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The initial ratio of sugar to flour in a dough was 2 : 7. To 9 kg of the dough John added more sugar to make the sugar to flour ratio 2 : 5. How much sugar did John later add?",
        "answer" : "1.2 kg"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The alcohol and water in a mixture are in the ratio of 7 : 8 respectively. If 11 litre water is added to it, then the ratio of alcohol and water in the new mixture becomes 3 : 5. What is the total quantity (in litres) of the alcohol in the new mixture?",
        "answer" : "21"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A mixture of 50 kg of cement and gravel contains 10% of gravel. How many kg of gravel must be added to make the gravel content 28% in the new mixture?",
        "answer" : "12.5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two mixtures have milk and water in the ratio 1 : 4 and 3 : 2 respectively. In what ratio two types of mixtures have to be mixed to get a new mixture having ratio of milk and water as 1 : 1?",
        "answer" : "1:3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Wheat costing Rs 30/kg, Rs 35/kg and a third variety of wheat are mixed in the ratio of 3 : 4 : 2. If the mixture is costs Rs 34/kg, then what will be the cost (in Rs/kg) of the third variety of wheat?",
        "answer" : "38"
    },
    {
        "question" : "X and Y are two alloys which are prepared by mixing zinc and aluminium in the ratio of 1 : 4 and 11 : 8 respectively. If equal quantities of alloys are melted to form a third alloy Z then what is the ratio of zinc and aluminium in alloy Z?",
        "answer" : "37:58"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In an alloy, aluminium and tin are in the ratio of 4 : 5. In the second alloy, the ratio of same elements is 4 : 7. If equal quantities of these two alloys be mixed to form a new alloy, then what will be the ratio of both of these elements in the new alloy?",
        "answer" : "40 :59"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A mixture contains spirit and water in the ratio of 3 : 2. If it contains 3 litres more spirit than water, the quantity of spirit in the mixture is",
        "answer" : "9 litres"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In an alloy of German silver. the ratio of copper to zinc was 21 : 16 while that of nickel to zinc was 7 : 24. What was the ratio of copper to zinc to nickel in the alloy?",
        "answer" : "63 : 48 : 14"
    },
    {
        "question" : "An 80 litre mixture of water and acid contains 20% acid. How much acid should be added to make the acid 60% in the new mixture?",
        "answer" : "80"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a mixture of 25 litres, the ratio of milk to water is 4:1. Another 3 litres of water is added to the mixture. The ratio of milk to water in the new mixture is",
        "answer" : "5:2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a mixture, water and milk are in the ratio of 3 : 5. In the second mixture, the ratio of water and milk is 9 : 11. If these two mixtures be mixed to form anew mixture in which water and milk are in ratio 5 : 7, then what is the ratio of these two mixtures in the new mixture?",
        "answer" : "4:5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "5 litres of honey contains 80% sugar. 3 litres of water is added to this honey. What is the percentage of sugar in the new mixture?",
        "answer" : "50"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio of sand to gravel in a mixture is 17:8 while that between gravel and cement is 6:17. What is the ratio of sand to cement in the mixture?",
        "answer" : "3:4"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a container, two types of liquids P and Q are in the ratio of 3 : 7. If 10 litres mixture is drawn off from the container and filled with 6 litres of liquid Q,then the ratio of P and Q becomes 1 : 3. What was the original quantity (in litres) of mixture?",
        "answer" : "40"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio should tea costing Rs 300/kg be mixed with tea costing Rs 200/kg so that the cost of the mixture is Rs 225/kg?",
        "answer" : "1:3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A jar contains a blend of a fruit juice and water in the ratio 5 : x. When 1 litre of water is added to 4 litres of the blend the ratio of fruit juice to water becomes 1 : 1. What is the value of x?",
        "answer" : "3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a mixture, unbroken and broken rice grains are in the ratio 3 : 2. How much fraction of the mixture must be drawn off and substituted with broken grains, so that the ratio of unbroken and broken grains becomes 1 : 1?",
        "answer" : "1/6"
    },
    {
        "question" : "50 litre mixture of water and alcohol contains 10% alcohol. How much more alcohol must be added to make the strength of alcohol 40% in the new mixture?",
        "answer" : "25"
    },
    {
        "question" : "20 kg of a mixture of wheat and husk contains 5% husk. How many kg more of husk must be added to make the husk content 20% in the new mixture?",
        "answer" : "3.75"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio of sand to gravel in a mixture is 7 : 8 while that between gravel and cement is 6 : 7. What is the ratio of sand to cement in the mixture?",
        "answer" : "3:4"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a mixture of milk and water, there is 19% milk. If the quantity of milk in the mixture is 437 mililitres, then what is the total quantity (in millilitres) of mixture?",
        "answer" : "2300"
    },
    {
        "question" : "An alloy contains copper and tin in the ratio 3 : 2. If 250 gm of copper is added to this alloy then the copper in it becomes double the quantity of tin in it. What is the amount (in gm) of tin in the alloy?",
        "answer" : "500"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In two types of brass, the ratios of Copper to Zinc are 8:3 and 15:7 respectively. If the two types of brass be melted and mixed in the ratio 5:2 a new type of brass is obtained. The ratio of Copper to Zinc in this new type of brass is",
        "answer" : "5:2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The milk and water in two vessels are in the ratio of 3 : 1 and 7 : 11 respectively. In what ratio should the liquid in both the vessels be mixed to obtaina new mixture containing half milk and half water?",
        "answer" : "4:9"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A milk merchant buys 50 litres of milk at the rate of Rs 40 per litre and mixes 5 litres of water in it. If he sells this mixture at the rate of Rs 42 per litre, then what is the profit percentage for the dealer?",
        "answer" : "15.5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many words can be formed by using 3 letters from the word “DELHI”",
        "answer" : "60"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many words can be formed by using the letters from the word “DRIVER” such that all the vowels are always together?",
        "answer" : "120"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many ways, can we select a team of 4 students from a given choice of 15?",
        "answer" : "1365"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many ways can a group of 5 members be formed by selecting 3 boys out of 6 boys and 2 girls out of 5 girls?",
        "answer" : "200"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many words can be formed by using the letters from the word “DRIVER” such that all the vowels are never together?",
        "answer" : "240"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many number greater than ten thousand can be formed from the digits 0, 1, 2, 3, 4 without repetition ? ",
        "answer" : "96"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many ways can 4 boys and 4 girls be seated around a circular table so that no two boys are in adjacent positions? ",
        "answer" : "3! x 4! "
    },
    {
        "question" : "Out of the 11 points in a plane, 4 are collinear. How many straight line can be formed ? ",
        "answer" : "50"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Twenty people attend a party and shake hands with one another.In how many ways hand shake is possible? ",
        "answer" : "190"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many different sums of money can be formed from the four type of notes Rs 10, Rs 20, Rs 50 and Rs 100 ?",
        "answer" : "15"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Five chocolates of different flavours are to be distributed in three different children such that any child get at least 1 chocolate. What is the maximum number of different ways in which this can be distributed?",
        "answer" : "150"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ram and his wife Sita both have five friends each. Ram has 2 boys and 3 girls. Sita has 3 boys and 2 girls. In how many maximum number of different ways can they invite 2 boys and 2 girls such that two of them are Ram’s friend and two are Sita’s friend?",
        "answer" : "46"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many ways can 4 notebooks can be distributed to 5 students if each can get any number of notebooks? ",
        "answer" : "5^4 ways. "
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many batting orders are possible for the Indian cricket team if there is a squad of 16 to choose from such that Virat Kohli and Rohit Sharma are always chosen? ",
        "answer" : "14C9 . 11! "
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many motor vehicle registration numbers plates can be formed for the state Haryana having code like (HR 12Q 8702) with the digits 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 and contains consonant at the alphabetical place(No digits being repeated).",
        "answer" : "95760"
    },
    {
        "question" : "From a group of 7 men and 6 women, five persons are to be selected to form a committee so that at least 3 men are there on the committee. In how many ways can it be done?",
        "answer" : "756"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many different ways can the letters of the word 'LEADING' be arranged in such a way that the vowels always come together?",
        "answer" : "720"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many different ways can the letters of the word 'CORPORATION' be arranged so that the vowels always come together?",
        "answer" : "50400"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Out of 7 consonants and 4 vowels, how many words of 3 consonants and 2 vowels can be formed?",
        "answer" : "25200"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many ways can the letters of the word 'LEADER' be arranged?",
        "answer" : "360"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a group of 6 boys and 4 girls, four children are to be selected. In how many different ways can they be selected such that at least one boy should be there?",
        "answer" : "209"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many 3-digit numbers can be formed from the digits 2, 3, 5, 6, 7 and 9, which are divisible by 5 and none of the digits is repeated?",
        "answer" : "20"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many ways a committee, consisting of 5 men and 6 women can be formed from 8 men and 10 women?",
        "answer" : "11760"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A box contains 2 white balls, 3 black balls and 4 red balls. In how many ways can 3 balls be drawn from the box, if at least one black ball is to be included in the draw?",
        "answer" : "64"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many different ways can the letters of the word 'DETAIL' be arranged in such a way that the vowels occupy only the odd positions?",
        "answer" : "36"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many ways can a group of 5 men and 2 women be made out of a total of 7 men and 3 women?",
        "answer" : "63"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many 4-letter words with or without meaning, can be formed out of the letters of the word, 'LOGARITHMS', if repetition of letters is not allowed?",
        "answer" : "5040"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many different ways can the letters of the word 'MATHEMATICS' be arranged so that the vowels always come together?",
        "answer" : "120960"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many different ways can the letters of the word 'OPTICAL' be arranged so that the vowels always come together?",
        "answer" : "720"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ways the letters of the word 'RUMOUR' can be arranged?",
        "answer" : "230"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ways the letters of the word 'PUZZLE' can be arranged to form the different new words so that the vowels always come together?",
        "answer" : "120"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ways can a group of 6 boys and 2 girls be made out of the total of 7 boys and 3 girls?",
        "answer" : "21"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Out of a group of 7 boys and 6 girls, five boys are selected to form a team so that at least 3 boys are there on the team. In how many ways can it be done?",
        "answer" : "756"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A box contains 2 red balls, 3 black balls, and 4 white balls. Find the number of ways by which 3 balls can be drawn from the box in which at least 1 black ball should be present",
        "answer" : "64"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Out of 7 constants and 4 vowels, how many words of 3 constants and 2 vowels can be formed?",
        "answer" : "25200"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How much 4-digit number can be formed from the digits 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, and 7 which are divisible by 5 in such a way that digits should not repeat.",
        "answer" : "60"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ways the letters of the word 'CRICKET' can be arranged to form the different new words so that the vowels always come together?",
        "answer" : "120"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ways the letters of the word ?MACHINE? can be arranged so that the vowels occupy only the odd positions?",
        "answer" : "576"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ways the letters of the word ?ACTORS? can arrange so that the vowels occupy only the even positions?",
        "answer" : "144"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Out of 7 consonants and 4 vowels, how many words of 3 consonants and 2 vowels can be formed?",
        "answer" : "25200"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Find the value of 'n' for which the nth term of two AP'S: 15,12,9.... and -15,-13,-11...... are equal?",
        "answer" : " n = 29/5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many different ways can the letters of the word 'LEADING' be arranged in such a way that the vowels always come together?",
        "answer" : "720"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A committee of 5 persons is to be formed from 6 men and 4 women. In how many ways can this be done when at least 2 women are included ?",
        "answer" : "186"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many arrangements can be made out of the letters of the word COMMITTEE, taken all at a time, such that the four vowels do not come together?",
        "answer" : "43200"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A college has 10 basketball players. A 5-member team and a captain will be selected out of these 10 players. How many different selections can be made?",
        "answer" : "1260"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many ways can a group of 5 men and 2 women be made out of a total of 7 men and 3 women?",
        "answer" : "63"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many different ways can the letters of the word 'OPTICAL' be arranged so that the vowels always come together?",
        "answer" : "720"
    },
    {
        "question" : "12 people at a party shake hands once with everyone else in the room.How many handshakes took place?",
        "answer" : "66"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In the below word how many words are there in which R and W are at the end positions? RAINBOW",
        "answer" : "240"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If the letters of the word SACHIN are arranged in all possible ways and these words are written out as in dictionary, then the word ‘SACHIN’ appears at serial number :",
        "answer" : "601"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many 4-letter words with or without meaning, can be formed out of the letters of the word, 'LOGARITHMS', if repetition of letters is not allowed?",
        "answer" : "5040"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many integers, greater than 999 but not greater than 4000, can be formed with the digits 0, 1, 2, 3 and 4, if repetition of digits is allowed?",
        "answer" : "376"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The Indian Cricket team consists of 16 players. It includes 2 wicket keepers and 5 bowlers. In how many ways can a cricket eleven be selected if we have to select 1 wicket keeper and atleast 4 bowlers?",
        "answer" : "1092"
    },
    {
        "question" : "When four fair dice are rolled simultaneously, in how many outcomes will at least one of the dice show 3?",
        "answer" : "671"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many 7 digit numbers can be formed using the digits 1, 2, 0, 2, 4, 2, 4?",
        "answer" : "360"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many different ways can the letters of the word 'DETAIL' be arranged in such a way that the vowels occupy only the odd positions?",
        "answer" : "36"
    },
    {
        "question" : "From 5 consonants and 4 vowels, how many words can be formed using 3 consonants and 2 vowels ?",
        "answer" : "7200"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A letter lock consists of three rings each marked with six different letters. The number of distinct unsuccessful attempts to open the lock is at the most  ?",
        "answer" : "215"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many ways can 4 girls and 5 boys be arranged in a row so that all the four girls are together ?",
        "answer" : "17280"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If the letters of the word CHASM are rearranged to form 5 letter words such that none of the word repeat and the results arranged in ascending order as in a dictionary what is the rank of the word CHASM ?",
        "answer" : "32"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many lines can you draw using 3 non collinear (not in a single line) points A, B and C on a plane?",
        "answer" : "3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many ways can 5 different toys be packed in 3 identical boxes such that no box is empty, if any of the boxes may hold all of the toys ?",
        "answer" : "25"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many ways a committee, consisting of 5 men and 6 women can be formed from 8 men and 10 women?",
        "answer" : "11760"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a Plane there are 37 straight lines, of which 13 pass through the point A and 11 pass through the point B. Besides, no three lines pass through one point, no lines passes through both points A and B , and no two are parallel. Find the number of points of intersection of the straight lines.",
        "answer" : "535"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many ways can 10 letters be posted in 5 post boxes, if each of the post boxes can take more than 10 letters ?",
        "answer" : " 5 ^ 10"
    },
    {
        "question" : "From a group of 7 men and 6 women, five persons are to be selected to form a committee so that at least 3 men are there on the committee. In how many ways can it be done?",
        "answer" : "756"
    },
    {
        "question" : "5 men and 4 women are to be seated in a row so that the women occupy the even places . How many such arrangements are possible?",
        "answer" : "2880"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a group of 6 boys and 4 girls, four children are to be selected. In how many different ways can they be selected such that at least one boy should be there?",
        "answer" : "209"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many arrangements of the letters of the word ‘BENGALI’ can be made if the vowels are to occupy only odd places.",
        "answer" : "576"
    },
    {
        "question" : "There are 7 non-collinear points. How many triangles can be drawn by joining these points?",
        "answer" : "35"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many different four letter words can be formed (the words need not be meaningful using the letters of the word 'MEDITERRANEAN' such that the first letter is E and the last letter is R?",
        "answer" : "59"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A polygon has 44 diagonals, then the number of its sides are ?",
        "answer" : "11"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a box, there are 5 black pens, 3 white pens and 4 red pens. In how many ways can 2 black pens, 2 white pens and 2 red pens can be chosen?",
        "answer" : "180"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A team of 8 students goes on an excursion, in two cars, of which one can seat 5 and the other only 4. In how many ways can they travel?",
        "answer" : "126"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many parallelograms will be formed if 7 parallel horizontal lines intersect 6 parallel vertical lines?",
        "answer" : "315"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many 6-digit even numbers can be formed from the digits 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 and 7 so that the digits should not repeat and the second last digit is even ?",
        "answer" : "720"
    },
    {
        "question" : "There are 6 bowlers and 9 batsmen in a cricket club. In how many ways can a team of 11 be selected so that the team contains at least 4 bowlers?",
        "answer" : "1170"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Find the number of subsets of the set {1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11} having 4 elements.",
        "answer" : "330"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Suppose 7 students are staying in a hall in a hostel and they are allotted 7 beds. Among them, Parvin does not want a bed next to Anju because Anju snores. Then, in how many ways can you allot the beds?",
        "answer" : "3600"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many arrangements can be made out of the letters of the word DRAUGHT, the vowels never beings separated?",
        "answer" : "1440"
    },
    {
        "question" : "There are 4 books on fairy tales, 5 novels and 3 plays. In how many ways can you arrange these so that books on fairy tales are together, novels are together and plays are together and in the order, books on fairytales, novels and plays ?",
        "answer" : "17280"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many different ways can the letters of the word 'THERAPY' be arranged so that the vowels never come together?",
        "answer" : "3600"
    },
    {
        "question" : "There are 5 novels and 4 biographies. In how many ways can 4 novels and 2 biographies can be arranged on a shelf ?",
        "answer" : "21600"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The number of ways in which 8 distinct toys can be distributed among 5 children?",
        "answer" : "5^8"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many different words can be made using the letters of the word ' HALLUCINATION ' if all constants are together?",
        "answer" : "1587600"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many necklace of 12 beads each can be made from 18 beads of different colours?",
        "answer" : "18!(6 x 24)"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A coach must choose five starters from a team of 12 players. How many different ways can the coach choose the starters ?",
        "answer" : "729"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The number of ways that 8 beads of different colours be strung as a necklace is ",
        "answer" : "2520"
    },
    {
        "question" : "There are three rooms in a Hotel: one single, one double and one for four persons. How many ways are there to house seven persons in these rooms ?",
        "answer" : "105"
    },
    {
        "question" : "12 points lie on a circle. How many cyclic quadrilaterals can be drawn by using these points?",
        "answer" : "495"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Consider the word ROTOR. Whichever way you read it, from left to right or from right to left, you get the same word. Such a word is known as palindrome. Find the maximum possible number of 5-letter palindromes.",
        "answer" : "17576"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many ways can the letters of the word 'PROBLEM' be rearranged to make 7 letter words such that none of the letters repeat?",
        "answer" : "7!"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Find the total numbers greater than 4000 that can be formed with digits 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 no digit being repeated in any number ?",
        "answer" : "192"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A group consists of 4 men, 6 women and 5 children. In how many ways can 2 men , 3 women and 1 child selected from the given group ?",
        "answer" : "600"
    },
    {
        "question" : "f nC10=nC12 then,find n.",
        "answer" : "22"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many ways can 5 letters be posted in 4 letter boxes?",
        "answer" : "1024"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If repetition of the digits is allowed, then the number of even natural numbers having three digits is :",
        "answer" : "450"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many arrangements of the letters of the word ‘BENGALI’ can be made if the vowels are never together.",
        "answer" : "720"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A box contains 2 white balls, 3 black balls and 4 red balls. In how many ways can 3 balls be drawn from the box, if at least one black ball is to be included in the draw?",
        "answer" : "64"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Compute the sum of 4 digit numbers which can be formed with the four digits 1,3,5,7, if each digit is used only once in each arrangement.",
        "answer" : "106656"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In How many ways is it possible to make a selection by taking any number of 15 fruits, namely 3 oranges, 5 apples and 7 mangoes?",
        "answer" : "191"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If there are 15 dots on a circle,how many triangles can be formed?",
        "answer" : "455"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A box contains 3 blue marbles, 4 red, 6 green marbles and 2 yellow marbles. If two marbles are picked at random, what is the probability that they are either blue or yellow ?",
        "answer" : "2/21"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many different ways can the letters of the word 'CORPORATION' be arranged so that the vowels always come together",
        "answer" : "50400"
    },
    {
        "question" : "There are 2 brothers among a group of 20 persons. In how many ways can the group be arranged around a circle so that there is exactly one person between the two brothers?",
        "answer" : "2 x 18!"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many ways can an animal trainer arrange 5 lions and 4 tigers in a row so that no two lions are together?",
        "answer" : "2880"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A Committee of 5 persons is to be formed from a group of 6 gentlemen and 4 ladies. In how many ways can this be done if the committee is to be included atleast one lady?",
        "answer" : "246"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Suppose you want to arrange your English, Hindi, Mathematics, History, Geography and Science books on a shelf. In how many ways can you do it?",
        "answer" : "720"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many alphabets need to be there in a language if one were to make 1 million distinct 3 digit initials using the alphabets of the language?",
        "answer" : "100"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many ways can the letters of the word ABACUS be rearranged such that the vowels always appear together?",
        "answer" : "(4! x 3!) / 2!"
    },
    {
        "question" : "From a total of six men and four ladies a committee of three is to be formed. If Mrs. X is not willing to join the committee in which Mr. Y is a member, whereas Mr.Y is willing to join the committee only if Mrs Z is included, how many such committee are possible?",
        "answer" : "91"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A Group consists of 4 couples in which each of the  4 persons have one wife each. In how many ways could they be arranged in a straight line such that the men and women occupy alternate positions?",
        "answer" : "1152"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many 3 letters words can be formed using the letters of the words hexagon?",
        "answer" : "210"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Suppose you can travel from a place A to a place B by 3 buses, from place B to place C by 4 buses, from place C to place D by 2 buses and from place D to place E by 3 buses. In how many ways can you travel ?from A to E?",
        "answer" : "72"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How many ways are there to select a subcommittee of 7 members from among a committee of 17?",
        "answer" : "19448"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A Group consists of 4 couples in which each of the  4 persons have one wife each. In how many ways could they be arranged in a straight line such that the men and women occupy alternate positions?",
        "answer" : "1152"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two outlet pipes A and B are connected to a full tank. Pipe A alone can empty the tank in 10 minutes and pipe B alone can empty the tank in 30 minutes. If both are opened together, how much time will it take to empty the tank completely?",
        "answer" : "7 minutes 30 seconds"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes X and Y attached to a swimming pool can fill the pool in 20 minutes and 30 minutes respectively working alone. Both were opened together but due to malfunctioning of motor of pipe X, it had to be shut down after two minutes but Y continued to work till the swimming pool was filled completely. Find the total time taken to fill the pool.",
        "answer" : "27"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Three pipes A, B and C were opened to fill a cistern. Working alone, A, B and C require 12, 15 and 20 minutes respectively.After 4 minutes of working together, A got blocked and after another 1 minute, B also got blocked. C continued to work till the end and the cistern got completely filled. What is the total time taken to fill the cistern ?",
        "answer" : "6 minutes 40 seconds"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Three pipes A, B and C are connected to a tank. Working alone, they require 10 hours, 20 hours and 30 hours respectively. After some time, A is closed and after another 2 hours, B is also closed. C works for another 14 hours so that the tank gets filled completely. Find the time (in hours) after which pipe A was closed.",
        "answer" : "2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Working alone, two pipes A and B require 9 hours and 6.25 hours more respectively to fill a pool than if they were working together. Find the total time taken to fill the pool if both were working together.",
        "answer" : "7.5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Three pipes A, B and C were opened to fill a cistern. Working alone, A, B and C require 12, 15 and 20 minutes respectively. Another pipe D, which is a waste pipe, can empty the filled tank in 30 minutes working alone. What is the total time (in minutes) taken to fill the cistern if all the pipes are simultaneously opened ?",
        "answer" : "6"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Three pipes A, B and C were opened to fill a tank. Working alone, A, B and C require 10, 15 and 20 hours respectively. A was opened at 7 AM, B at 8 AM and C at 9 AM. At what time the tank would be completely filled, given that pipe C can only work for 3 hours at a stretch, and needs 1 hour standing time to work again.",
        "answer" : "12 : 30 PM"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes A and B can fill a tank in 10 hours and 30 hours respectively. Due to a leak in the tank, it takes 2.5 hours more to fill the tank. How much time would the leak alone will take to empty the tank ?",
        "answer" : "30 hours"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes A and B work alternatively with a third pipe C to fill a swimming pool. Working alone, A, B and C require 10, 20 and 15 hours respectively. Find the total time required to fill the pool.",
        "answer" : "6 hours 54 minutes"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes A and B are connected to drain out a water tank. A alone can drain out the tank in 20 hours and B can drain 20 liters per hour. Find the capacity of the water tank given that working together, they require 12 hours to completely drain out the tank",
        "answer" : "600"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two friends A and B decided to work together and fill a pool of capacity 1000 liters. Using a bucket each, A fills at the rate of 4 liters every 3 minutes and B fills at 3 liters every 4 minute. What would be the total time required to fill the pool, given that they take a break of 3 minutes each time both of them put a bucket into the pool at the same instant ?",
        "answer" : "9 hours 57 minutes"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two taps A and B can fill a tank in 10 hours and 15 hours respectively. If both the taps are opened together, the tank will be full in ?",
        "answer" : "6 hr"
    },
    {
        "question" : "To fill a cistern, pipes A, B and C take 15 minutes, 12 minute and 10 minutes respectively. The time in minutes that the three pipes together will take to fill the cistern is:",
        "answer" : "4 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes can fill a tank in 10 hours and 12 hours respectively, while third pipe empties the full tank in 20 hours. If all the three pipes operate simultaneously, in how much time the tank will be filled?",
        "answer" : "7 hr. 30 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A cistern can be filled in 9 hours but it takes 10 hours due to a leak in its bottom. If the cistern is full, then the time that the leak will take to empty it is:",
        "answer" : "90 hr"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Three pipes A, B and C can fill a tank from empty to full in 30 minutes, 20 minutes, and 10 minutes respectively. When the tank is empty, all the three pipes are opened. A, B and C discharge chemical solutions P,Q and R respectively. What is the proportion of the solution R in the liquid in the tank after 3 minutes?",
        "answer" : "6/11"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipes A and B can fill a tank in 5 and 6 hours respectively. Pipe C can empty it in 12 hours. If all the three pipes are opened together, then the tank will be filled in:",
        "answer" : "60/17 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A pump can fill a tank with water in 2 hours. Because of a leak, it took 2 hours to fill the tank. The leak can drain all the water of the tank in:",
        "answer" : "14 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes A and B can fill a cistern in 37 minutes and 45 minutes respectively. Both pipes are opened. The cistern will be filled in just half an hour, if the B is turned off after:",
        "answer" : "9 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A tank is filled by three pipes with uniform flow. The first two pipes operating simultaneously fill the tank in the same time during which the tank is filled by the third pipe alone. The second pipe fills the tank 5 hours faster than the first pipe and 4 hours slower than the third pipe. The time required by the first pipe is:",
        "answer" : "15 hours"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes can fill a tank in 20 and 24 minutes respectively and a waste pipe can empty 3 gallons per minute. All the three pipes working together can fill the tank in 15 minutes. The capacity of the tank is:",
        "answer" : "120 gallons"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A tank is filled in 5 hours by three pipes A, B and C. The pipe C is twice as fast as B and B is twice as fast as A. How much time will pipe A alone take to fill the tank?",
        "answer" : "35 hours"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes A and B together can fill a cistern in 4 hours. Had they been opened separately, then B would have taken 6 hours more than A to fill the cistern. How much time will be taken by A to fill the cistern separately?",
        "answer" : "6 hours"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes A and B can fill a tank in 20 and 30 minutes respectively. If both the pipes are used together, then how long will it take to fill the tank?",
        "answer" : "12 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes A and B can fill a tank in 15 minutes and 20 minutes respectively. Both the pipes are opened together but after 4 minutes, pipe A is turned off. What is the total time required to fill the tank?",
        "answer" : "14 min. 40 sec"
    },
    {
        "question" : "One pipe can fill a tank three times as fast as another pipe. If together the two pipes can fill the tank in 36 minutes, then the slower pipe alone will be able to fill the tank in:",
        "answer" : "144 min."
    },
    {
        "question" : "A large tanker can be filled by two pipes A and B in 60 minutes and 40 minutes respectively. How many minutes will it take to fill the tanker from empty state if B is used for half the time and A and B fill it together for the other half?",
        "answer" : "30 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A tap can fill a tank in 6 hours. After half the tank is filled, three more similar taps are opened. What is the total time taken to fill the tank completely?",
        "answer" : "3 hrs 45 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Three taps A, B and C can fill a tank in 12, 15 and 20 hours respectively. If A is open all the time and B and C are open for one hour each alternately, the tank will be full in:",
        "answer" : "7 hours"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Three pipes A, B and C can fill a tank in 6 hours. After working at it together for 2 hours, C is closed and A and B can fill the remaining part in 7 hours. The number of hours taken by C alone to fill the tank is:",
        "answer" : "14"
    },
    {
        "question" : " It takes 6 hours for three pipes, X, Y and Z to fill a tank. When the three worked together for 2 hours, Z was closed and, X and Y filled the remaining tank in 7 hours. How many hours would it take Z alone to fill the tank?",
        "answer" : "14 hours"
    },
    {
        "question" : "It takes two pipes A and B, running together, to fill a tank in 6 minutes. It takes A 5 minutes less than B to fill the tank, then what will be the time taken by B alone to fill the tank?",
        "answer" : "15 minutes"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If two pipes can fill a tank in 24 and 20 minutes respectively and another pipe can empty 3 gallons of water per minute from that tank. When all the three pipes are working together, it takes 15 minutes to fill the tank. What is the capacity of the tank? ",
        "answer" : "120 gallons"
    },
    {
        "question" : "It takes 20 minutes for pipe A to fill the tank completely and it takes 30  minutes for pipe B to fill the tank completely. If both the inlets are opened together, then how much time will be taken to fill the tank completely? ",
        "answer" : "12 minutes"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes A and B can fill a tank in 15 minutes and 20 minutes respectively. Both the pipes are opened together but after 4 minutes, pipe A is turned off. What is the total time required to fill the tank?",
        "answer" : "14 min. 40 sec."
    },
    {
        "question" : "A water tank is two-fifth full.Pipe A can fill a tank in 10 minutes and pipe B can empty it in 6 minutes.If both the pipes are open,how long will it take to empty or fill the tank completely?",
        "answer" : "6 min.to empty"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A tap can fill a tank in 6 hours. After half the tank is filled, three more similar taps are opened. What is the total time taken to fill the tank completely?",
        "answer" : " 3 hrs 45 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A pump can fill a tank with water in 2 hours. Because of a leak, it took 2(1/3) hours to fill the tank. The leak can drain all the water of the tank in:",
        "answer" : "14 hours"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A cistern is normally filled in 8 hours but takes two hours longer to fill because of a leak in its bottom. If the cistern is full, the leak will empty it in    ?",
        "answer" : " 20 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Three pipes A, B and C can fill a tank in 6 hours. After working at it together for 2 hours, C is closed and A and B can fill the remaining part in 7 hours. The number of hours taken by C alone to fill the tank is:",
        "answer" : "14"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Three taps A,B and C can fill a tank in 12,15 and 20 hours respectively. If A is open all the time and B ,C are open for one hour each alternatively, the tank will be full in:",
        "answer" : "7 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Taps X and Y can fill a tank in 30 and 40 minutes respectively.Tap Z can empty the filled tank in 60 minutes.If all the three taps are kept open for one minute each,how much time will the taps take to fill the tank?",
        "answer" : "24min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A cistern has a leak which would empty the cistern in 20 minutes. A tap is turned on which admits 4 liters a minute into the cistern, and it is emptied in 24 minutes. How many liters does the cistern hold ?",
        "answer" : "480 lit"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes can fill a tank in 20 and 24 minutes respectively and a waste pipe can empty 3 gallons per minute. All the three pipes working together can fill the tank in 15 minutes. The capacity of the tank is:",
        "answer" : " 120 gallons"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A large tanker can be filled by two pipes A and B in 60 and 40 minutes respectively. How many minutes will it take to fill the tanker from empty state if B is used for half the time and A and B fill it together for the other half ?",
        "answer" : "30 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "12 buckets of water fill a tank when the capacity of each tank is 13.5 liters. How many buckets will be needed to fill the same tank,if the capacity of each bucket is 9 liters?",
        "answer" : "18"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes A and B can separately fill a cistern in 10 and 15 minutes respectively. A person opens both the pipes together when the cistern should have been was full he finds the waste pipe open. He then closes the waste pipe and in another 3 minutes the cistern was full. In what time can the waste pipe empty the cistern when fill  ?",
        "answer" : "8.57 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "One fill pipe A is 3 times faster than second fill pipe B and takes 32 minutes less than the fill pipe B. When will the cistern be full if both pipes are opened together?",
        "answer" : "12 minutes"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipe A can fill a tank in 16 minutes and pipe B cam empty it in 24 minutes. If both the pipes are opened together after how many minutes should pipe B be closed, so that the tank is filled in 30 minutes  ?",
        "answer" : "21 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "One pipe can fill a tank  three times as fast as another pipe. If together the two pipes can fill the tank in 36 min, then the slower alone will be able to fill the tank in:",
        "answer" : "144 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Water flows into a tank which is 200 m long and 150 m wide, through a pipe of cross-section (0.3m x 0.2m) at 20 km/h. In what time will the water level be 12m  ?",
        "answer" : " 300 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A and B can fill the tank in 60 min and 90 min. There is a leak at 3/4th of the height. If leak is opened alone, it takes 36 min to empty till 3/4th the height. Find the time taken to fill the tank if all of the taps and the leak are opened simultaneously.",
        "answer" : "39"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what time would a cistern be filled by three pipes which diameters are 2 cm, 3 cm and 4 cm running together, when the largest alone can fill it is 58 minutes? The amount of water flowing in each pipe is proportional to the square of its diameter.",
        "answer" : "32 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes A and B can fill a tank in 15 min and 20 min respectively. Both the pipes are opened together but after 4 min, pipe A is turned off. What is the total time required to fill the tank ?",
        "answer" : "14 min 40 sec."
    },
    {
        "question" : "Three taps I, J and K can fill a tank in 20,30and 40 minutes respectively. All the taps are opened simultaneously and after 5 minutes tap A was closed and then after 6 minutes tab B was closed .At the moment a leak developed which can empty the full tank in 70 minutes. What is the total time taken for the completely full ?",
        "answer" : "26.166 minutes"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes A and B can fill a tank in 16 hrs and 12 hrs respectively. The capacity of the tank is 240 liters. Both the pipes are opened simultaneously and closed after 2 hrs. How much more water need to fill the tank?",
        "answer" : "170 lit"
    },
    {
        "question" : "There is an empty reservoir whose capacity is 30 litres. There is an inlet pipe which fills at 5 L/min and there is an outlet pipe which empties at 4 L/min. Both the pipes function alternately for 1 minute. Assuming that the inlet pipe is the first one to function, how much time will it take for the reservoir to be filled up to its capacity?",
        "answer" : "51 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes A and B can separately fill a cistern in 60 min and 75 min respectively. There is a third pipe in the bottom of the cistern to empty it. If all the three pipes are simultaneously opened, then the cistern is full in 50 min. In how much time, the third pipe alone can empty the cistern ?",
        "answer" : "100 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipe K fills a tank in 30 minutes. Pipe L can fill the same tank 5 times as fast as pipe K. If both the pipes were kept open when the tank is empty, how much time will it take for the tank to overflow ?",
        "answer" : "5 minutes"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A tap can fill a tank in 6 hours. After half the tank is filled three more similar taps are opened. What is the total time taken to fill the tank completely ?",
        "answer" : "3 hrs 45 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A Tank is normally filled in 9 hours but takes four hours longer to fill because of a leak in its bottom. If the tank is full, the leak will empty it in ?",
        "answer" : " 29.25 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A water tank in a village is normally filled in 8 hours but takes 2 hours longer to fill because of a leak in its bottom. If the tank is full, in how many hrs will the leak empty it ? ",
        "answer" : "40 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio of efficiencies of two filling pipes is 4 : 5. There is a third emptying pipe which efficiency is two third of the average efficiency of first two filling pipes can empty a filled tank in 36 minutes. In how much time both the filling pipes can fill the tank when it is empty?",
        "answer" : " 12 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The capacity of a tank is 2400 m3.  A pump can be used both for filling and emptying the tank.  The emptying capacity of the pump is 10 m3/minute higher than its filling capacity. And also, the pump needs 8 minutes less to empty the tank than to fill it. Find the filling capacity of the pump.",
        "answer" : "50 cub.m/min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A tank is filled in eight hours by three pipes K, L and M. Pipe K is twice as fast as pipe L, and L is twice as fast as M. How much time will pipe L alone take to fill the tank ?",
        "answer" : "28 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two filling taps P and Q together can fill a tank with rate of 40 lit/min and 60 lit/min respectively in 8 min. If a waste tap can empty the filled tank in 32 min, then what is the rate of waste tap ?",
        "answer" : "25 lit/min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipe A is an inlet pipe that can fill an empty cistern in 69 hours. Pipe B can drain the filled cistern in 46hours. When the cistern was filled the two pipes are opened one at a time for an hour each, starting withPipe B. how long will it take for the cistern to be empty?",
        "answer" : " 11 days 7 hours"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A water tank is filled in 5 hours by three pipes X, Y and Z the pipe Z is thrice as fast as Y and Y is twice as fast as X. How much time will pipe X alone take to fill the water tank?",
        "answer" : "45 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipes A and B can fill a cistern in 15 hours together. But ifthese pipes operate separately A takes 40 hours less than Bto fill the tank. In how many hours the pipe A will fill thecistern working alone?",
        "answer" : "20"
    },
    {
        "question" : "3 pipes when opened for 3 hours can fill 3 buckets. How many buckets can 2 pipes open for 2 hours approximately fill?",
        "answer" : "4/3 bucket"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A water tank has holes. The 1st hole alone empties the tank in 9 min and 2nd hole alone empties the tank in 6 min. If water leaks out at a constant rate, how many min does it take if both the holes together empty the tank?",
        "answer" : " 3(3/5)"
    },
    {
        "question" : "One pipe can fill a tank three times as fast as another pipe. If together the two pipes can fill tank in 36 min, then the slower pipe alone will be able to fill the tank in ?",
        "answer" : "144 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes, when working one at a time, can fill a cistern in 3 hhrs and 4 hrs, resp while a third pipe can drain the cistern empty in 8 hrs. All the three pipes were opened together when the cistern was 1/12 full. How long did it take for the cistern to be completely full?",
        "answer" : "2 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two taps X and Y can fill a tank in 15 hours and 20 hours respectively. If the two taps are opened at 2 p.m., then at what time (in p.m.) should the tap X be closed to completely fill the tank at exactly 2 a.m.?",
        "answer" : "8"
    },
    {
        "question" : "18 buckets of water fill a tank when the capacity of each bucket is 8 litres. How many buckets will be needed to fill the same tank, if the capacity of the bucket is 12 litres?",
        "answer" : " 12"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A cistern has one inlet, L and one inlet, M. L takes 5 hours to fill the empty tank, when M is not open and M takes 8 hours to empty the full tank, if the tank is two fifth full, how much time will it take to fill the tank completely when both L and M are opened simultaneously? (in hours)",
        "answer" : "8 hours"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A swimming pool is filled in 10 hours by three tankers A, B and C. The tanker C is twice as fast as B and B is twice as fast as A. How much time will tanker A alone take to fill the swimming pool?",
        "answer" : "70 hours"
    },
    {
        "question" : "One pipe can fill an empty cistern in 4 hours while another can drain the cistern when full in 10 hours. Both the pipes were turned on when the cistern was half-empty. How long will it take for the cistern to be full?",
        "answer" : " 3 hours 20 minutes"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two taps P and Q can fill a tank in 24 hours and 18 hours respectively. If the two taps are opened at 11 a.m., then at what time (in p.m.) should the tap P be closed to completely fill the tank at exactly 2 a.m.?",
        "answer" : "3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "One of the two inlet pipes works twice as efficiently as the other. The two, working alongside a drain pipe that can empty a cistern all by itself in 8 hours, can fill the empty cistern in 8 hours. How many hours will the less efficient inlet pipe take to fill the empty cistern by itself?",
        "answer" : "12"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Three pipe P, Q and R can fill a tank in 12 minutes, 18 minutesand 24 minutes respectively. The pipe R is closed 12 minutesbefore the tank is filled. In what time the tank is full?",
        "answer" : "8 (4/13) hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipe A is an inlet pipe that can fill an empty cistern in 8.7 hours. Pipe B can drain a filled cistern in 5.8 hours. When the cistern was filled the two pipes are opened one at a time for an hour each, starting with Pipe B. How long will it take for the cistern to be empty?",
        "answer" : "30 hours 48 minutes  "
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes X and Y can individually fill a tank in 48 and 72 min respectively. If they are opened simultaneously, how long will it take for the tank to fill? ",
        "answer" : "28.8 min "
    },
    {
        "question" : "A water tank is 2/5 th full. Inlet A can fill the tank in 12 minutes while an outlet pipe B can empty it in 6minutes. If both the pipes are open, how long will it take to empty or fill the tank completely?",
        "answer" : " It empties in 4.8 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes fill a tank when working individually in 25 and 40 hours, respectively while a third pipe can drain the filled tank in 16 hours. If all the three pipes are turned on at the same time when the tank is empty, how long will it take to fill the tank completely ?",
        "answer" : "16 days 16 hours"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A tank can be filled in 30 minutes. There is a leakage which can empty the tank in 90 minutes. Therefore, the tank will be filled in",
        "answer" : "45 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes X and Y can fill an empty tank in 16 hours and 20 hours respectively. Pipe Z alone can empty the completely filled tank in 25 hours. Firstly both pipes X and Y are opened and after 6 hours pipe Z is also opened. What will be the total time (in hours) taken to completely fill the tank?",
        "answer" : "304/29"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Sita's bucket has thrice the capacity as Ramu's bucket. It takes 60 turns for Sita's bucket to fill the empty drum. How many turns it will take for both the buckets of Sita's and Ramu's, having each turn together to fill the empty drum?",
        "answer" : "45"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipes A, B, and C are attached to an empty cistern. While the first two can fill the cistern in 4 and 10 hours, respectively, the third can drain the cistern, when filled, in 6 hours. If all the three pipes are opened simultaneously when the cistern is three-fifth full, how many hours will be needed to fill the cistern?",
        "answer" : "24/11"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes can fill a cistern in 28 and 21 hours respectively and an another pipe can empty 30 gallons of water per hour. All the three pipes working together can fill the empty cistern in 84 hours. What is the capacity (in gallons) of the cistern?",
        "answer" : "420"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Raghu's tanker can fill a cistern in 4 hours. After half the cistern is filled, three more similar tankers are opened. What is the total time taken to fillthe cistern completely?",
        "answer" : "2h 30 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Working together, pipes A and B can fill an empty tank in 10 hours. They worked together for 4 hours and then B stopped and A continued filling the tank till it was full. It took a total of 13 hours to fill the tank. How long would it take A to fill the empty tank alone?",
        "answer" : "15 hours"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two valves P and B can fill a sump in 37.5 minutes and 45 minutes respectively. Both valves are opened. The sump will be filled in just 30 minutes, if valve B is turned off after",
        "answer" : "9 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipes A and C can fill an empty cistern in 32 and 48 hrs, respectively while Pipe B can drain the filled cistern in 24hrs. If the three pipes are turned on together when the cistern is empty, how many hrs will it take for the cistern to be 2/3 full?",
        "answer" : "64"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipes A and B, when working together, can fill an empty tank in 8 hours. If B is stopped after 2 hours, it will take a total of 11 hrs to fill the tank. How long would it take A to fill the empty tank alone?",
        "answer" : "12 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes namely A,B can fill a sump in 25 minutes and half an hour respectively and a pipe C can empty 3 gallons per minute. All the three pipes working together can fill the tank in 15 minutes. The capacity off the tank is",
        "answer" : "450 gallons"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipe A can empty a filled tank in 28 hours while Pipe B can fill the same tank, when empty in 35 hrs. If alternatively Pipes A and B are turned on for an hour each time, starting when the tank is full, how long will it take to empty the tank?",
        "answer" : "271 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipes A and B, when working together, can fill an empty tank in 24 hours. They work together for 8 hours and then B is stopped but A continued to work. It took a total of 28 hours to fill the tank. How long would it take A to fill the empty tank alone?",
        "answer" : "30 hours"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipe A can fill an empty cistern in 4 hours while along with Pipe B it can fill it up in 3 hours. Only Pipe A is turned on for an hour after which Pipe B is also turned on. How much total time will it take to fill up the cistern?",
        "answer" : "3 hrs 15 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipe A can fill an empty cistern in 5 hours while Pipe B lakes 6.25 hours to fill it. The two pipes are opened simultaneously when the cistern is empty, but Pipe B is turned off after some time as a result of which the cistern is filled in 3.4 hours. For how many hours was Pipe B open?",
        "answer" : " 2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A pipe can fill a sump with water in 2 hours. Because of a leak, it took 2 2/3 hrs to fill the sump. The leak can drain all the water of the sump in",
        "answer" : "8 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipe C and D alone can fill a tank in 4 and 5 hours, respectively. If pipe C is closed after 3 hours and at the same time pipe D is opened. in how many hours will the tank get filled?",
        "answer" : "1.25"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes, when working one at a time can fill a cistern in 2 hrs and 3 hrs, respectively while a third pipe can drain the cistern empty in 6 hrs. All the three pipes were opened together when the cistern was 1/6 full. How long will it take for the cistern to be completely full?",
        "answer" : " 1 hour 15 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A pipe can fill a tank in 12 hours. By mistake another pipe that empties the tank is left open and the tank is filled in 16 hours. If the tank is fill, how much time will the second pipe take to empty it?",
        "answer" : "48 hours"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipes A, B and C are attached to an empty cistern. While the first two can fill the cistern in 4 and 10 hrs, respectively, the third can drain the cistern, when filled, in 6 hrs. If all the three pipes are opened simultaneously when the cistern is half-full, how many hours will be needed to fill the cistern?",
        "answer" : " 30/11"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sump is filled by three tankers with uniform flow. The first two tankers operating simultaneously fill the sump in the same time during which the sump is filled by the third tanker alone. The second tanker fills the sump 5 hours faster than the first tanker and 4 hours slower than the third tanker. The time required by the first tanker is:",
        "answer" : "15hours"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two pipes P and Q can fill an empty tank in 25 hours and 20 hours respectively. Pipe R alone can empty the completely filled tank in 50 hours. Firstly both the pipes P and Q are opened and after 8 hours pipe R is also opened. What will be the total time (in hours) taken to completely fill the tank?",
        "answer" : "12"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A flask has two holes. The 1st hole alone makes the flask empty in 9 minutes and 2nd hole alone makes the flask empty in 16 minutes. If water leaks out at a constant rate, how long in minutes does it take if both the holes together empty the flask?",
        "answer" : "51925"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A pump can fill a tank in 4 hrs, but due to a leak, the tank now gets filled in 5 hrs. How long will it take the leakage to empty the tank when it is full?",
        "answer" : " 9 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipes A and C can fill an empty cistern in 7 and 10.5 hours, respectively while Pipe B can drain the filled cistern in 5.25 hours. If the three pipes are turned on together when the cistern is empty, how many hours will it take for the cistern to be 2/3 full?",
        "answer" : "14"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A water tank has two holes. The 1st hole alone makes the tank empty in 3 min and 2nd hole alone makes the tank empty in 5 min. If water leaks out at a constant rate, how long in minutes does it take if both the holes together empty the tank?",
        "answer" : "15/8"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Pipe A can fill an empty cistern in 6 hours while along with Pipe B it can fill it up in 4 hours. Only Pipe B is on for an hour after which Pipe A is also turned on. How much time will it take in all to fill up the cistern?",
        "answer" : "4 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person buys a pen from a wholesaler at Rs. 10 for 20 pens. He sells those pens at Rs. 10 for 15 pens. Find his profit percent.",
        "answer" : "33.334%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A dealer incurs a loss of 5 % if he sells an article for Rs. 1805. What price must he sell the article so as to gain 5 % on that article? ",
        "answer" : "Rs. 1995 "
    },
    {
        "question" : " If the cost price of an article is 67 % of the selling price, what is the profit percent? ",
        "answer" : "49.25 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : " A shopkeeper purchased two varieties of rice, 80 KG at Rs. 13.50 per KG and 120 KG at Rs. 16 per KG. The shopkeeper being greedy, mixed the two varieties of rice and sold the mixture at a gain of 16 %. Find the per KG selling price of the mixture.",
        "answer" : "Rs. 17.40"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A seller claims to sell at cost price but gives 750 gm for each KG. Find his gain percent. ",
        "answer" : "33.334 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man sold two watches at the same price, one at a 10 % profit and the other at a 10 % loss. Find his overall gain or loss percentage. ",
        "answer" : "Let the selling price of each watch be Rs. 99 S => Total SP = Rs. 198 S CP of first watch = SP – Profit = Rs. 99 S- 10 % of CP = Rs. 90 S CP of second watch = SP + Loss = Rs. 99 S + 10 % of CP = Rs. 110 S => Total CP = Rs. 90 S + 110 S = Rs. 200 S => Loss = Total CP – Total SP = 200 – 198 = Rs. 2 S Therefore, loss percent = (Loss / CP) x 100 = (2 S / 200 S) x 100 % = 1 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A shopkeeper gives two successive discounts of 20 % and 10 % on surplus stock. Further, he also gives a 5 % extra discount on cash payments. If a person buys a shirt from the surplus stock and pays in cash, what overall discount percent will he get on the shirt? ",
        "answer" : "31.60 % "
    },
    {
        "question" : "A dealer wants to mark the price of an article such that by offering a 5 % discount, he is able to get 33 % profit. Find the percent of CP above which the article should be marked. ",
        "answer" : "40 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The cost price of 12 books is equal to the selling price of 10 books. The gain percent is :",
        "answer" : "20 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If the loss% on article is 15%. Then the ratio of cost price and selling price will be",
        "answer" : "CP : SP = 20 : 17"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ram goes from place P to Q to buy an article costing 20% less at Q. Although he spends Rs 200 on travelling, still he gains Rs 200 compared to buying at P. His profit percent is:",
        "answer" : "10%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The price of a TV and a refrigerator set are in ratio 3:5. If the refrigerator cost Rs 4400 more than the TV set, then the price of the TV is",
        "answer" : "Rs 6600"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A house and a shop were sold for Rs. 1 lakh each. In this transaction, the house sale resulted into 20% loss whereas the shop sale into 20% profit. The entire transaction resulted in:",
        "answer" : "1/12 lakh"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A shopkeeper sells a chair at a profit of 20%. If he had bought the table at 10% less cost and sold for Rs 60 more, he would have gained 40%. The cost price of the chair is:",
        "answer" : "Rs 1000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "By selling a bicycle of Rs 3360 a shopkeeper gain 12%. If the profit is reduced to 8%, then the selling price will be",
        "answer" : "Rs 3240"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man purchased an article of Rs 2500 and sold it at 40% above the cost price. If he has to pay Rs 250 as tax on it his net profit percentage will be:",
        "answer" : "30%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sells an item to B at a profit of 25%. B sells it to C at a profit of 20%. If C pays Rs 900 for it, the cost price of the bicycle for A is :",
        "answer" : "600"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A increase of 20% in the price of apple enabled a purchaser to obtain 4 apple less of Rs 72. The price of 16 apple before increase was :",
        "answer" : "24 apples = Rs 72 ; 1 apple = Rs 3 ; 16 apples = Rs 48"
    },
    {
        "question" : "By selling 100 oranges, a shopkeeper gains the selling price of 20 oranges. His gain percent is",
        "answer" : "25%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A dealer makes a profit of 20% even after giving a 10% discount on the advertised price of a scooter.If he makes a profit of Rs 7200 on the sale of the scooter, the advertise price was",
        "answer" : "Rs. 48000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A shopkeeper allows a discount of 22% on the marked price. How much above the cost price must he mark his goods as to gain 17%?",
        "answer" : "50%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Alfred buys an old scooter for Rs. 4700 and spends Rs. 800 on its repairs. If he sells the scooter for Rs. 5800, his gain percent is:",
        "answer" : "(300 / 5500) * 100"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The cost price of 20 articles is the same as the selling price of x articles. If the profit is 25%, then the value of x is:",
        "answer" : "16"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If selling price is doubled, the profit triples. Find the profit percent.",
        "answer" : "100"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a certain store, the profit is 320% of the cost. If the cost increases by 25% but the selling price remains constant, approximately what percentage of the selling price is the profit?",
        "answer" : "70%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A vendor bought toffees at 6 for a rupee. How many for a rupee must he sell to gain 20%?",
        "answer" : "5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The percentage profit earned by selling an article for Rs. 1920 is equal to the percentage loss incurred by selling the same article for Rs. 1280. At what price should the article be sold to make 25% profit?",
        "answer" : "2000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A shopkeeper expects a gain of 22.5% on his cost price. If in a week, his sale was of Rs. 392, what was his profit?",
        "answer" : "Rs.72"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man buys a cycle for Rs. 1400 and sells it at a loss of 15%. What is the selling price of the cycle?",
        "answer" : "Rs.1190"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Sam purchased 20 dozens of toys at the rate of Rs. 375 per dozen. He sold each one of them at the rate of Rs. 33. What was his percentage profit?",
        "answer" : "5.6"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Some articles were bought at 6 articles for Rs. 5 and sold at 5 articles for Rs. 6. Gain percent is:",
        "answer" : "44%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "On selling 17 balls at Rs. 720, there is a loss equal to the cost price of 5 balls. The cost price of a ball is:",
        "answer" : "Rs.60"
    },
    {
        "question" : "When a plot is sold for Rs. 18,700, the owner loses 15%. At what price must that plot be sold in order to gain 15%?",
        "answer" : "Rs.25,300"
    },
    {
        "question" : "100 oranges are bought at the rate of Rs. 350 and sold at the rate of Rs. 48 per dozen. The percentage of profit or loss is:",
        "answer" : "(100/7)%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A shopkeeper sells one transistor for Rs. 840 at a gain of 20% and another for Rs. 960 at a loss of 4%. His total gain or loss percent is:",
        "answer" : "(100/17)%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A trader mixes 26 kg of rice at Rs. 20 per kg with 30 kg of rice of other variety at Rs. 36 per kg and sells the mixture at Rs. 30 per kg. His profit percent is:",
        "answer" : "5%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A  shopkeeper sold an article for Rs. 2500. If the cost price of the article is 2000, find the profit percent.",
        "answer" : "25%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man purchases a TV for Rs. 8000 and sells it at 10% loss. What is the selling price of T.V?",
        "answer" : "Rs.7200"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ramesh bought a chair for Rs. 1540 and sold it to Suresh. If Ramesh earned a profit of 25%, find the selling price of chair.",
        "answer" : "Rs.1925"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A shopkeeper purchases a table and sells it for Rs. 4200. If he incurs a loss of 20%, find the cost price of table.",
        "answer" : "Rs.5250"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Suresh bought a cell phone from a shop. If he sells it at Rs. 8400 to Mahesh and earns a profit of 12%, find the price at which Suresh bought the cell phone.",
        "answer" : "Rs.7500"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A shopkeeper bought a watch for Rs. 1200. At what price should he sell the watch to earn a profit of 25% ?",
        "answer" : "Rs.1500"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Mohan bought an article at 25% less of the marked price and sold it at 15% more than the marked price. Find the profit earned by him.",
        "answer" : "53.3%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If the cost price of 120 mangoes is equal to the selling price of 100 mangoes, what is the profit percent in this transaction?",
        "answer" : "20%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "After selling 140 apples a fruit seller earns a profit equal to S.P. of 20 apples. His profit percentage is:",
        "answer" : "16.7%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "he cost price of 30 articles is equal to the selling price of 25 articles. What is the profit percentage in this transaction?",
        "answer" : "20%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man earns a profit of 20% on selling price. Find the profit percent on the cost price.",
        "answer" : "25%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The owner of the cell phone shop charges 23% more than the cost price. If a customer paid 7011 for a cell phone, find the cost price of the cell phone.",
        "answer" : "5700"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The profit percent gained if an object is sold at Rs 464 is equals to the loss percent when the object is sold at Rs 436. Find the cost price of this object?",
        "answer" : "450"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A shopkeeper sells an article for Rs 78 and earns double the profit that he would have earned on selling this article for Rs 69. Find the C.P of this article",
        "answer" : "60"
    },
    {
        "question" : "By selling an object for Rs 900, a man earns a profit that is double the loss incurred when the object is sold for Rs 450. If he sells it at a profit of 20%, find the selling price of this object.",
        "answer" : "720"
    },
    {
        "question" : "By selling a property for Rs 45000 a person incurs a loss of 10%. Find the selling price to gain the profit of 15 %?",
        "answer" : "57500"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person purchases some article at the rate of 4 articles for rupees 5 and sells them at the rate of 5 articles for rupees 4. Find the total profit or loss in %.",
        "answer" : "20% loss"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A shopkeeper purchases some article at the rate of 2 articles for rupees 3 and purchases twice of the quantity at the rate of 3 articles for rupees 2. He sells them at the rate of 6 articles for rupees 7. Find the profit or loss %.",
        "answer" : "23.52% profit"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A shopkeeper sells his goods at a profit of 10%. If he had purchased it at 20% less and sells it at rupees 10 more, he had a gain of 40%. Find the C.P of the goods.",
        "answer" : "500"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The C.P of an article is equaled to the profit %, and a shopkeeper sells it in Rs 56. Find the C.P of the article.",
        "answer" : "C.P = Profit% = 40"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The marked price of a radio is Rs 480. The owner allows a discount of 10% and still earns the profit of 8%. If no discount is allowed, find his gain percent?",
        "answer" : "20%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "5% more is gained by selling a cow for Rs 1010 than by selling it for Rs 1000. What is the C.P of the cow?",
        "answer" : "Rs 200"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A dishonest milkman sells milk at cost price, but he mixes water and earns 16(2/3) % profit. Find the ratio of mixture and milk in the mixture.",
        "answer" : "7:8"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ayaan bought 30 kg of rice at the rate of Rs 9.50/ kg and 40 kg rice at the rate of Rs 8.50/kg and mixed them. He sold the mixture at the rate of Rs. 8.90/kg. Find his total profit or loss in the transaction.",
        "answer" : "Rs 2 loss"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If a retail seller buys 30 pencils at the marked price of 27 pens, find the profit percent.",
        "answer" : "11(1/9)%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If selling price is doubled, the profit triples. Find the profit percent ?",
        "answer" : "100%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A trader mixes 26 kg of rice at Rs. 20 per kg with 30 kg of rice of other variety at Rs. 36 per kg and sells the mixture at Rs. 30 per kg. His profit percent is:",
        "answer" : "5%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "By selling 45 lemons for Rs 40, a man loses 20%. How many should he sell for Rs 24 to gain 20% in the transaction ?",
        "answer" : "18"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If the cost price of 12 pens is equal to the selling price of 8 pens, the gain percent is ?",
        "answer" : "50%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A milkman purchases the milk at Rs. x per litre and sells it at Rs. 2x per litre still he mixes 2 litres water with every 6 litres of pure milk. What is the profit percentage?",
        "answer" : "166.66%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If books bought at prices ranging from Rs. 200 to Rs. 350 are sold at prices ranging from Rs. 300 to Rs. 425, what is the greatest possible profit that might be made in selling eight books ?",
        "answer" : "1800"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Cost of 3 cricket balls = cost of 2 pairs of leg pads.Cost of 3 pairs of leg pads = cost of 2 pairs of gloves. Cost of 3 pairs of gloves = cost of 2 cricket bats. If a cricket bat costs Rs 54, what is the cost of a cricket ball. ",
        "answer" : "Rs. 16"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The percentage profit earned by selling an article for Rs. 1920 is equal to the percentage loss incurred by selling the same article for Rs. 1280. At what price should the article be sold to make 25% profit?",
        "answer" : "Rs.2000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If the cost price is 25% of selling price. Then what is the profit percent.",
        "answer" : "300%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Tarun got 30% concession on the labelled price of an article and sold it for Rs. 8750 with 25% profit on the price he bought. What was the labelled price ?",
        "answer" : "10000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A Shopkeeper sells two articles at Rs.1000 each, making a profit of 20% on the first article and a loss of 20% on the second article. Find the net Profit or loss that he makes? ",
        "answer" : "4%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person incurs a loss of 5% be selling a watch for Rs. 1140. At what price should the watch be sold to earn 5% profit.",
        "answer" : "Rs.1260"
    },
    {
        "question" : "By selling an article at Rs.800, a shopkeeper makes a profit of 25%.At what price should he sell the article so as to make a loss of 25%?",
        "answer" : "Rs.480"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What profit percent is made by selling an article at a certain price, if by selling at 2/3rd of that price, there would be a loss of 20% ?",
        "answer" : "20%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man buys oranges at Rs 5 a dozen and an equal number at Rs 4 a dozen. He sells them at Rs 5.50 a dozen and makes a profit of Rs 50. How many oranges does he buy?",
        "answer" : "50 dozens"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Due to reduction of 25% in price of oranges a customer can purchase 4 oranges more for Rs. 16. what is original price of an orange?",
        "answer" : "Rs. 1.33"
    },
    {
        "question" : "On selling 17 balls at Rs. 720, there is a loss equal to the cost price of 5 balls. The cost price of a ball is ?",
        "answer" : "Rs.60"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Bhajan Singh purchased 120 reams of paper at Rs 80 per ream. He spent Rs 280 on transportation, paid octroi at the rate of 40 paise per ream and paid Rs 72 to the coolie. If he wants to have a gain of 8 %, what must be the selling price per ream?",
        "answer" : "90"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a scheme, a pack of three soaps with MRP Rs.45 is available for Rs.42. If it still gives a profit of 5% to the shopkeeper, then the cost price of the pack is ?",
        "answer" : "40"
    },
    {
        "question" : "'A' sold an article to 'B' at a profit of 20%. 'B' sold the same article to 'C' at a loss of 25% and 'C' sold the same article to 'D' at a profit of 40%. If 'D' paid Rs 252 for the article, then find how much did 'A' pay for it?",
        "answer" : "Rs.200"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A trader sold an article at a loss of 5% but when he increased the selling price by Rs.65 he gained 3.33% on the cost price. If he sells the same article at Rs. 936, what is the profit percentage?",
        "answer" : "20%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The cost price of 20 articles is the same as the selling price of x articles. If the profit is 25%, then the value of x is:",
        "answer" : "16"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Every year before the festive season,a shopkeeper increases the price of the product by 35% and then introduce two successive discount of 10% and 15% respectively.what is percentage loss and percentage gain ?",
        "answer" : "3.27 % gain"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The sale price of an article including the sales tax is Rs. 616. The rate of sales tax is 10%. If the shopkeeper has made a profit of 12%, then the cost price of the article is :",
        "answer" : "Rs.500"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A shopkeeper sells one-third of his goods at a profit of 10%, another one-third at a profit of 20%, and the rest at a loss of 6%.What is his overall profit percentage ?",
        "answer" : "8%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If goods be purchased for Rs.450 and 1/3 is sold at a loss of 10%. At what gain % should the remainder is sold to has to gain 20% on the whole transaction?",
        "answer" : "35%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A dealer sold two of his cattle for Rs. 500 each. On one of them he lost 10% on the other, he gained 10%. His gain or loss percent in the entire transaction was:",
        "answer" : "1% loss"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If the manufacturer gains 10 %, the wholesale dealer 15 % and the retailer 25 %, then find the cost of production of a table if the retail price was Rs 1265",
        "answer" : "Rs.800"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man bought an article and sold it at a gain of 5 %. If he had bought it at 5% less and sold it for Re 1 less, he would have made a profit of 10%. The C.P. of the article was",
        "answer" : "Rs.200"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The profit earned by selling an article for Rs. 832 is equal to the loss incurred when the same article is sold for Rs. 448. What should be the sale price for making 50% profit ?",
        "answer" : "Rs.960"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The cash difference between the selling prices of an article at a profit of 4% and 6% is Rs 3. The ratio of two selling prices is",
        "answer" : "52:53"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A, B and C invest in the ratio of 3 : 4: 5. The percentage of return on their investments are in the ratio of  6 : 5 : 4. Find the total earnings, If B earns Rs. 250 more than A :",
        "answer" : "Rs. 7250"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ajay bought 15 kg of dal at the rate of Rs 14.50 per kg and 10 kg at the rate of Rs 13 per kg. He mixed the two and sold the mixture at the rate of Rs 15 per kg. What was his total gain in this transaction ?",
        "answer" : "Rs 27.50"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Rahul went to purchase a Nokia mobile handset, the shopkeeper told him to pay 20% tax if he asked the bill. Rahul manages to get the discount of 5% on the actual saleprice of the mobile and he paid the shopkeeper Rs. 3325 without tax. Besides he manages to avoid to pay 20% tax on the already  discounted price, what is the amount of discount that he has gotten?",
        "answer" : "Rs 875"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sweet seller sells 3/5th part of sweets at a profit of 10% and remaining at a loss of 5%. If the total profit is Rs 1500, then what is the total cost price of sweets ?",
        "answer" : "Rs.37,500"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what ratio should water and wine be mixed so that after selling the mixture at the cost price a profit of 33.33% is made?",
        "answer" : "1:3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man saves 20% of his monthly salary. If an account of dearness of things he is to increase his monthly expenses by 15%, he is only able to save Rs. 400 per month. What is his monthly salary ?",
        "answer" : "Rs. 5000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If the selling price of a mat is five times the discount offered and if the percentage of discount is equal to the percentage profit, find the ratio of the discount offered to the cost price.",
        "answer" : "7:30"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A guy walks into a store and steals Rs. 100 from the store without the owner's knowledge. He then buys Rs. 60 worth of goods using that Rs. 100 and the owner gies Rs. 40 in change. How much money did the owner lose?",
        "answer" : "Rs.100"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A milk man has 20 liters of milk. If he mixes 5 liters of water, which is freely available, in 20 liters of pure milk.If the cost of pure milk is Rs.18 per liter,then the profit of the milkman, when he sells all the mixture at cost price is:",
        "answer" : "25%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person sold two cows each for Rs.9900. If he gained 10% on one and lost 20% on the other, then which of the following is true?",
        "answer" : " Net loss = 2475 - 900 = 1575"
    },
    {
        "question" : "By mixing two qualities of pulses in the ratio 2: 3 and selling the mixture at the rate of Rs 22 per kilogram, a shopkeeper makes a profit of 10 %. If the cost of the smaller quantity be Rs 14 per kg, the cost per kg of the larger quantity is:",
        "answer" : "Rs.24"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A merchant buys two articles for Rs.600. He sells one of them at a profit of 22% and the other at a loss of 8% and makes no profit or loss in the end. What is the selling price of the article that he sold at a loss ?",
        "answer" : "Rs. 404.80"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A retailer buys a radio for Rs 225. His overhead expenses are Rs 15. He sellis the radio for Rs 300. The profit percent of the retailer is",
        "answer" : "25%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A car mechanic purchased four old cars for Rs. 1 lakh. He spent total 2 lakh in the maintenance and repairing of these four cars. what is the average sale price of the rest three cars to get 50% total profit if he has already sold one of the four cars at Rs. 1.2 lakh?",
        "answer" : "1.1 lakh"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man buys an item at Rs. 1200 and sells it at the loss of 20 percent. Then what is the selling price of that item",
        "answer" : "Rs. 960"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The marked price of an article is increased  by 25% and the selling price is increased by 16.66%, then the amount of profit doubles. If the original marked price  be Rs. 400 which is greater than the corresponding cost price by 33.33% , what is the increased selling price?",
        "answer" : "420"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If the cost price of a certain object doubles, then the loss gets tripled of what it was initially. The initial loss % was ?",
        "answer" : "50 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A shopkeeper fixes the marked price of an item 35% above its cost price. The percentage of discount allowed to gain 8% is",
        "answer" : "20%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A seller uses 840 gm in place of 1 kg to sell his goods. Find his actual profit/loss % When he sells his article on 4% loss on cost price ?",
        "answer" : "14.28 % profit"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Arun purchased 30 kg of wheat at the rate of Rs. 11.50 per kg and 20 kg of wheat at the rate of 14.25 per kg. He mixed the two and sold the mixture. Approximately what price per kg should be sell the mixture to make 30% profit ?",
        "answer" : "Rs. 16.30"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio of the cost price and selling price of a shirt is 32 : 37. What is the profit percentage?",
        "answer" : "15.63"
    },
    {
        "question" : "K purchased a table for Rs.11,000 and sold it for Rs.13,500. What is his gain in percentage?",
        "answer" : "22.7%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A shopkeeper sold a mobile phone for Rs. 12000. Had he offered discount of 10% on the selling price, there would be a loss of 4%. What is the cost price of that Mobile phone?",
        "answer" : "Rs. 11,250"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A milkman has 20 liters of milk. If he mixes 5 liters of water, which is freely available, in 20 liters of pure milk. If the cost of pure milk is Rs. 18 per litre, then the profit of the milkman, when he sells all the mixture at  cost price, is:",
        "answer" : "25%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two successive discounts of 5% and 15% are given by Rakesh on a table. If the marked price of the table is Rs 2000, then what is the value (in Rs) of discount",
        "answer" : "Rs.385"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Find the SI on rupees 10000 deposited for 3 years at 5% per annum.",
        "answer" : "Interest earn is rupees 1,500"
    },
    {
        "question" : " Rajesh takes a loan of Rs 20000 from a bank for a period of 1 year. The rate of interest is 10% per annum. Find the simple interest and the total amount he has to pay at the end of a year.",
        "answer" : "Rs 22,000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person borrowed Rs 60,000 for 4 years at the rate of 2.5% per annum. Find the interest accumulated at the end of 4 years.",
        "answer" : "Rs 6000 "
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person pays Rs 8000 as an amount on the sum of Rs 6000 that he had borrowed for 3 years. What will be the rate of interest?",
        "answer" : "Rate of interest R is 11.11 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : " If the principal is Rs 50,000, and the rate of interest is 10% per annum for a period of 4 years. What will be the total amount?",
        "answer" : "Rs 70000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If the principal amount is Rs 5000 and the time is 2 years and the simple interest is Rs 4000 what will be the rate of interest?",
        "answer" : "Rate of Interest is 40 %."
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum amounts to Rs 1065 at simple interest rate of 7.5% per annum after 3 years. Find the sum.",
        "answer" : "869.38"
    },
    {
        "question" : "James deposits a sum of Rs 800 that will amount to Rs 920 in 3 years. However, the bank decides to increase the interest rate by 4%. What amount will he receive now?",
        "answer" : "Rs 1016"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What will be the simple interest on Rs 70,000 at 50/3 % per annum after 9 months?",
        "answer" : "Rs 8750"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Find out the simple interest if Harry invests an amount of Rs 15800 for 9 months at the rate of 25/4 % per annum. ",
        "answer" : "Rs 740.63"
    },
    {
        "question" : "After lending out an amount of Rs.9600 at a rate of 9/2 % per annum for a 1 year and 9 months, what was the S.I earned ? ",
        "answer" : "756"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Find the amount of S.I received by Ram after getting Rs.3360 at 25/4 % per annum for 9 months.",
        "answer" : "157.5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ram has an amount of Rs. 9000. How much time will it take to earn 1620 as S.I at a rate of 4.5% per annum?",
        "answer" : "4"
    },
    {
        "question" : "At what rate of SI, a sum of Rs.7000 amounts to Rs.7700 in 2 years?",
        "answer" : "5%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Find the simple interest on Rs.300 for 6 months at 10% per annum.",
        "answer" : "15"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what time will Rs.8500 pay an amount of Rs. 7267.50 as S.I at 4.5 per cent per annum?",
        "answer" : "19"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The SI on a sum is 1/4th of the principal, and the duration(in years) is equal to the rate per cent per annum. Find the rate per cent.",
        "answer" : "5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The rate of interest for the first 2 yrs is 3% per annum, for the next 3 years is 8% per annum and for the period beyond 5 years 10% per annum. A person deposited some money 6 years back. Now he earns an interest of RS. 1520. What money did he deposit?",
        "answer" : "3800"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of money doubles itself in 6 years at simple interest. What is the rate of interest?",
        "answer" : "16.66"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A certain amount was lent at a rate R for 2 yrs at SI. If it been put at 3% higher rate, it would have fetched Rs 300 more. Find the amount?",
        "answer" : "5000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of money at simple interest amounts to Rs. 815 in 3 years and to Rs. 854 in 4 years. The sum is:",
        "answer" : "Rs. 698"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Mr. Thomas invested an amount of Rs. 13,900 divided in two different schemes A and B at the simple interest rate of 14% p.a. and 11% p.a. respectively. If the total amount of simple interest earned in 2 years be Rs. 3508, what was the amount invested in Scheme B?",
        "answer" : "Rs. 6400"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum fetched a total simple interest of Rs. 4016.25 at the rate of 9 p.c.p.a. in 5 years. What is the sum?",
        "answer" : "Rs. 8925"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How much time will it take for an amount of Rs. 450 to yield Rs. 81 as interest at 4.5% per annum of simple interest?",
        "answer" : "4 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Reena took a loan of Rs. 1200 with simple interest for as many years as the rate of interest. If she paid Rs. 432 as interest at the end of the loan period, what was the rate of interest?",
        "answer" : "6"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of Rs. 12,500 amounts to Rs. 15,500 in 4 years at the rate of simple interest. What is the rate of interest?",
        "answer" : "6%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "An automobile financier claims to be lending money at simple interest, but he includes the interest every six months for calculating the principal. If he is charging an interest of 10%, the effective rate of interest becomes:",
        "answer" : "10.25%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A lent Rs. 5000 to B for 2 years and Rs. 3000 to C for 4 years on simple interest at the same rate of interest and received Rs. 2200 in all from both of them as interest. The rate of interest per annum is:",
        "answer" : "10%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of Rs. 725 is lent in the beginning of a year at a certain rate of interest. After 8 months, a sum of Rs. 362.50 more is lent but at the rate twice the former. At the end of the year, Rs. 33.50 is earned as interest from both the loans. What was the original rate of interest?",
        "answer" : " 3.46%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man took loan from a bank at the rate of 12% p.a. simple interest. After 3 years he had to pay Rs. 5400 interest only for the period. The principal amount borrowed by him was:",
        "answer" : "Rs. 15,000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of money amounts to Rs. 9800 after 5 years and Rs. 12005 after 8 years at the same rate of simple interest. The rate of interest per annum is:",
        "answer" : "12%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What will be the ratio of simple interest earned by certain amount at the same rate of interest for 6 years and that for 9 years?",
        "answer" : "2 : 3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A certain amount earns simple interest of Rs. 1750 after 7 years. Had the interest been 2% more, how much more interest would it have earned?",
        "answer" : "Since the principal is not given, so data is inadequate."
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person borrows Rs. 5000 for 2 years at 4% p.a. simple interest. He immediately lends it to another person at 6% p.a for 2 years. Find his gain in the transaction per year.",
        "answer" : "Rs. 112.50"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Rs. 800 becomes Rs. 956 in 3 years at a certain rate of simple interest. If the rate of interest is increased by 4%, what amount will Rs. 800 become in 3 years",
        "answer" : "1052"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many years Rs 150 will produce the same interest at 8% as Rs. 800 produce in 3 years at 9/2%",
        "answer" : "9"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of money amounts to Rs 9800 after 5 years and Rs 12005 after 8 years at the same rate of simple interest. The rate of interest per annum is",
        "answer" : "12%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The rate of interest for the first 2 years is 4% per annum, for the next 3 years is 7.5% per annum and for the period beyond 5 years 12.5% per annum. If a man gets Rs 1075 as a simple interest for 6 years, how much money did he deposit?",
        "answer" : "3000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Thiru took a loan at 10% p.a. S.I. After 4 years, he returned the principal along with the interest. If he returns in all Rs. 3500, what is the principal amount?",
        "answer" : "2500"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Find the simple interest on Rs 7000 at 50/3 % for 9 months",
        "answer" : "875"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Find the simple interest on the Rs. 2000 at 25/4% per annum for the period from 4th Feb 2005 to 18th April 2005",
        "answer" : "25"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If A lends Rs. 3500 to B at 10% p.a. and B lends the same sum to C at 11.5% p.a., then the gain of B (in Rs.) in a period of 3 years is",
        "answer" : "157.5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "At what rate percent per annum will the simple interest on a sum of money be 2/5 of the amount in 10 years",
        "answer" : "4"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum becomes five times of itself in 20 years. It will become 7 times itself in how many years?",
        "answer" : "30"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Some amount out of Rs. 7,000 was lent at 6% per annum and the remaining at 4% per annum. If the total simple interest from both the fractions in 5 years was Rs. 1600, the sum lent at 6% per annum was:",
        "answer" : "2000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Thiru has invested Rs. 5000 for 2 years at the rate of 8%. How much more money he should invest at the rate of 15% to get the overall interest of 10%? (Assume Simple interest)",
        "answer" : "2000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of Rs. 1550 was lent partially at 5% and partially at 8% per annum simple interest. The total interest received after 4 years was Rs. 400. The ratio of the money lent at 5% to that lent at 8% is:",
        "answer" : "16:15"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What annual payment will discharge a debt of Rs.6450 due in 4 years at 5% simple interest?",
        "answer" : "Rs.1500"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of Rs.6450 is borrowed at 5% simple interest and is paid back in 4 equal annual installments. What is amount of each installment?",
        "answer" : "Rs.1800"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What will be the simple interest on Rs. 80,000 at 16(2/3) % per annum for 9 months?",
        "answer" : "10,000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Find the simple interest on Rs. 5000 at 6 % per annum for the period from 5th Feb to 19th April, 2015.",
        "answer" : " Rs. 60"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Suresh borrows Rs. 10,000 for 2 years at 4 % p.a. simple interest. He lends it to Ramesh at 6 % p.a. for 2 years. Find his gain in this transaction per year.",
        "answer" : "Rs. 200"
    },
    {
        "question" : "At what rate percent per annum will sum of money double in 20 years?",
        "answer" : " 5 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : "John took a loan of Rs. 1500 with simple interest for as many years as the rate of interest. If he paid Rs. 540 as interest at the end of loan period, what was the rate of interest?",
        "answer" : "6 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : " A sum of Rs. 12,000 amounts to Rs. 15,000 in 4 years at the rate of simple interest. Find the rate of interest.",
        "answer" : "6.25 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Nikhil borrowed some money at the rate of interest 5 % p.a. for first 2 years, 8 % p.a. for next 5 years and 10 % p.a. for a period beyond 7 years. If he pays total interest of Rs. 8000 at the end of 10 years, then find the money Nikhil borrowed.",
        "answer" : " Rs. 10,000"
    },
    {
        "question" : " A sum was put at simple interest at a certain rate for 2 years. Had it been put at 2 % higher rate, it would have fetched Rs. 400 more. Find the sum.",
        "answer" : "10000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The S.I. on a certain sum of money for 4 years at 15 % per annum is Rs. 180 more than S.I. on same sum for 5 years at 10 % per annum. Find the sum.",
        "answer" : " 1800"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The difference between two numbers is 1550. If 8 % of one number is 10 % of the other number, then find the two numbers",
        "answer" : "6200, 7750"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two numbers P and Q are such that, the sum of 2 % of P and Sum of 2 % of Q is two-third of the sum of 2 % of P and 6 % of Q. Find the ratio of P and Q.",
        "answer" : "3 : 1"
    },
    {
        "question" : "50 % of a number is 18 less than two-third of that number. Find the number.",
        "answer" : "108"
    },
    {
        "question" : "When 35 is subtracted from a number; it reduces to its 80 %. Find the four-fifth of that number.",
        "answer" : "140"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The value of lathe machine depreciates at the rate of 10 % per annum. If the cost of machine at present is Rs. 160,000, then what will be its worth after 2 years?",
        "answer" : " Rs. 129,600"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The value of Xerox machine depreciates at the rate of 10 % per annum. If the cost of machine at present is Rs. 75,000 then what was the value of machine before 2 years?",
        "answer" : "Rs. 92,600"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The current birth rate per thousand is 30, whereas corresponding death rate is 10 per thousand. Find the net growth rate in terms of population increase in percent.",
        "answer" : "2 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The total population of a city is 6500.The number of males and females increases by 5 % and 10 % respectively and consequently the population becomes 7000. Find the number of males in the village.",
        "answer" : "3000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The present population of a country is 10 crores. If it rises to 17.28 crores during next 3 years, then find uniform rate of growth in population.",
        "answer" : "20 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The population of different trees in a field increased by 10 % in first year, increased by 8 % in second year and decreased by 10 % in third year. If at present the number of trees is 26730, then find the number of tress in the beginning.",
        "answer" : "25000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The price of diesel increases by 50 %. Find by how much percent a truck owner must reduce his consumption in order to maintain the same budget?",
        "answer" : "33.33 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The price of rice falls by 15 %. By what percentage a person can increase the consumption of rice so that his overall budget does not change?",
        "answer" : "17.64 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In an examination, P scored 30 % marks and failed by 15 marks. Q scored 40 % marks and obtained 35 marks more than those required to pass. Find the pass percentage.",
        "answer" : "33 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : " In a science examination, the average obtained by entire class was 80 marks. If 10 % of students scored 92 marks and 20 % of students scored 90 marks, then what was the average of remaining students?",
        "answer" : " 75.43"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A student attempts x number of questions. He answers 15 correctly out of first 20 questions and of the remaining questions, he answers 1/3 correctly. If all questions have same credit and the student gets 50 % marks, then find the value of x.",
        "answer" : "50"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man took loan from a bank at the rate of 12% p.a. simple interest. After 3 years he had to pay Rs. 5400 interest only for the period. The principal amount borrowed by him was:",
        "answer" : "Rs.15000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "At what rate percent per annum will a sum of money double in 8 years.",
        "answer" : "12.5%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How much time will take for an amount of Rs. 450 to yield Rs. 81 as interest at 4.5% per annum of simple interest  ?",
        "answer" : "4 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A certain sum of money amounts to Rs 1008 in 2 years and to Rs 1164 in 3 ½  years. Find the sum and the rate of interest.",
        "answer" : "800, 13%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of money at simple interest amounts to Rs. 815 in 3 years and to Rs. 854 in 4 years. The sum is:",
        "answer" : "698"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What annual instalment will discharge a debt of Rs 1092 due in 3 years at 12% simple interest?",
        "answer" : "Rs.325"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person borrows Rs. 5000 for 2 years at 4% p.a. simple interest. He immediately lends it to another person at 6(1/4) p.a for 2 years. Find his gain in the transaction per year",
        "answer" : "Rs. 112.50"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum was put at simple interest at a certain rate for 3 years. Had it been put at 2% higher rate, it would have fetched Rs 360 more. Find the sum.",
        "answer" : " Rs.6000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Simple interest on a certain sum is 16/25 of the sum. Find the rate percent and time, If both are numerically equal.",
        "answer" : "Rate = 8% and Time = 8 years."
    },
    {
        "question" : "A father left a will of Rs.35 lakhs between his two daughters aged 8.5 and 16 such that they may get equal amounts when each of them reach the age of 21 years. The original amount of Rs.35 lakhs has been instructed to be invested at 10% p.a. simple interest. How much did the elder daughter get at the time of the will?",
        "answer" : "21 lakhs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of Rs.1550 was lent partly at 8% p.a. simple interest. The total interest received after 3 years was Rs.300. The ratio of the money lent at 5% to that lent at 8% is :",
        "answer" : "16:15"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In how many years will a sum of Rs.800 at 10% per annum compounded semi annually become Rs.926.10",
        "answer" : "1.5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "At what rate of compound interest per annum will a sum of rs.1200 becomes rs.1348.32 in 2 years",
        "answer" : "66%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A certain amount earns simple interest of Rs. 1750 after 7 years. Had the interest been 2% more, how much more interest would it have earned?",
        "answer" : "We need to know the S.I, principal and time to find the rate. Since the principal is not given, so data is inadequate."
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of Rs. 725 is lent in the beginning of a year at a certain rate of interest. After 8 months, a sum of Rs. 362.50 more is lent but at the rate twice the former. At the end of the year, Rs. 33.50 is earned as interest from both the loans. What was the original rate of interest?",
        "answer" : "3.46%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Find: S.l. on Rs 6250 at 14% per annum for 146 days.",
        "answer" : " Rs.350"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of money becomes 7/6 of itself in 3 years at a certain rate of simple interest. The rate per annum is ?",
        "answer" : "50/9 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A Certain sum of money an amounts to Rs 2500 in a span Of 5 years and further to Rs.3000 in a span of 7 years at simple interest The sum is ?",
        "answer" : "Rs. 1250"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of Rs. 12,500 amounts to Rs. 15,500 in 4 years at the rate of simple interest. What is the rate of interest",
        "answer" : " 6%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The difference between the simple interest received from two different sources on Rs.1500 for 3 years is Rs.13.50. The difference between their rates of interest is",
        "answer" : "0.3%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man borrowed Rs 24000 from two money lenders. For one loan, he paid 15% per annum and for the other 18% per annum. At the end of one year, he paid Rs 4050. How much did he borrow at each rate ?",
        "answer" : "Rs.15000"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How long will it take for a sum of money to grow from Rs.1250 to Rs.10,000, if it is invested at 12.5% p.a simple interest?",
        "answer" : "56years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum was put at simple interest at a certain rate for 10 years . Had it been put at 5% higher rate , it would have fetched Rs.600 more. What was the Sum?",
        "answer" : " Rs.1200"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The interest on a certain deposit at 4.5% p.a. is Rs. 202.50 in one year. How much will the additional interest in one year be on the same deposit at 5% p.a.  ?",
        "answer" : "Rs. 22.5"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of money amounts to Rs. 9800 after 5 years and Rs. 12005 after 8 years at the same rate of simple interest. The rate of interest per annum is:",
        "answer" : " 12%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person takes a loan of Rs. 200 at 5% simple interest. He returns Rs.100 at the end of one year. In order clear his dues at the end of 2 years, he would pay : ",
        "answer" : "Rs. 115"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Rs.1500 is divided into two parts such that if one part is invested at 6% and the other at 5% the whole annual interest from both the sum is Rs.85. How much was lent at 5% ?",
        "answer" : "Rs. 500"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of money invested for a certain number of years at 8% p.a. simple interest grows to Rs.180. The same sum of money invested for the same number of years at 4% p.a. simple interest grows to Rs.120 only. For how many years was the sum invested?",
        "answer" : "25years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If the C.I. on a sum for 2 years at 12 1/2 % per annum is Rs. 510, the S.I. on the same sum at the same rate for the same period of time is   ?",
        "answer" : "Rs. 480"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A sum of money triples itself in 8 years simple interest. Find the rate of percent per annum?",
        "answer" : "25%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The simple interest on Rs. 25 for 4 months at the rate of 3 paise per rupee per month is :",
        "answer" : " Rs. 3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The simple interest on Rs.10 for 4 months at the rate of 3 paise per month is",
        "answer" : " 1.2 Paise"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The simple interest on a sum of money will be Rs.600 after 10 years. If the principal is trebled after 5 years what will be the total interest at the end of the tenth year ?",
        "answer" : " Rs. 1200"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What will be the ratio of simple interest earned by certain amount at the same rate of interest for 6 years and that for 9 years?",
        "answer" : "2:3"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How much time will it take for an amount of Rs. 450 to yield Rs. 81 as interest at 4.5% per annum of simple interest?",
        "answer" : "4 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : "An automobile financier claims to be lending money at S.I., but he includes the interest every six months for calculating the principal. If he is charging an interest of 8%, the effective rate of interest becomes ?",
        "answer" : "8.16 %"
    },
    {
        "question" : "An automobile financier claims to be lending money at simple interest, but he includesthe interest every six months for calculating the principal. If he is charging an interest of10%, the effective rate of interest becomes:",
        "answer" : "10.25%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Reena took a loan of Rs. 1200 with simple interest for as many years as the rate of Interest. If she paid Rs. 432 as interest at the end of the loan period, what was the rate of interest?",
        "answer" : "6"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A Rent Rs. 5000 to B for 2 years and Rs. 3000 to C for 4 years on simple interest at the same rate of interest and received Rs. 2200 in all from both of them as interest. The rate of interest per annum is:",
        "answer" : "10%"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what time will Rs. 1860 amount to Rs. 2641.20 at simple interest 12% per annum?",
        "answer" : "3.5 years"
    },
    {
        "question" : " A runner can complete a 750 m race in two and a half minutes. Will he be able to beat another runner who runs at 17.95 km/hr? ",
        "answer" : "Speed of the first runner = 18 km / hr . Also, we are given that the speed of the second runner is 17.95 km/hr. Therefore, the first runner can beat the second runner."
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man decided to cover a distance of 6 km in 84 minutes. He decided to cover two-thirds of the distance at 4 km/hr and the remaining at some different speed. Find the speed after the two-third distance has been covered.",
        "answer" : "5 km / hr "
    },
    {
        "question" : " A postman traveled from his post office to a village in order to distribute mail. He started on his bicycle from the post office at a speed of 25 km/hr. But, when he was about to return, a thief stole his bicycle. As a result, he had to walk back to the post office on foot at the speed of 4 km/hr. If the traveling part of his day lasted for 2 hours and 54 minutes, find the distance between the post office and the village.",
        "answer" : "10km"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Walking at the speed of 5 km/hr from his home, a geek misses his train by 7 minutes. Had he walked 1 km/hr faster, he would have reached the station 5 minutes before the actual departure time of the train. Find the distance between his home and the station. ",
        "answer" : "6 km"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two stations B and M are 465 km distant. A train starts from B towards M at 10 AM with a speed of 65 km/hr. Another train leaves from M towards B at 11 AM at a speed of 35 km/hr. Find the time when both trains meet. ",
        "answer" : "Thus, the trains meet at 4 hours after 11 AM, i.e., 3 PM. "
    },
    {
        "question" : "A policeman sighted a robber from a distance of 300 m. The robber also noticed the policeman and started running at 8 km/hr. The policeman also started running after him at the speed of 10 km/hr. Find the distance that the robber would run before being caught.",
        "answer" : "Distance run by the robber = 8 x 0.15 = 1.2 km "
    },
    {
        "question" : "To cover a certain distance, a geek had two options, either to ride a horse or to walk. If he walked one side and rode back the other side, it would have taken 4 hours. If he had walked both ways, it would have taken 6 hours. How much time will he take if he rode the horse both ways?",
        "answer" : "2 hours "
    },
    {
        "question" : "A train running at a speed of 36 km/hr and 100 meter long. Find the time in which it passes a man standing near the railway line is : ",
        "answer" : "36 km/hr "
    },
    {
        "question" : "If an employee walks 10 km at a speed of 3 km/hr, he will be late by 20 minutes. If he walks at 4 km/hr, how early from the fixed time he will reach ? ",
        "answer" : "30 minutes"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The diameter of each wheel of a truck is 140 cm, If each wheel rotates 300 times per minute then the speed of the truck (in km/hr) (take pi=22/7) ",
        "answer" : "79.2 km/hr "
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man drives at the rate of 18 km/hr, but stops at red light for 6 minutes at the end of every 7 km. The time that he will take to cover a distance of 90 km is ",
        "answer" : "6 hour 12 minute "
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two jeep start from a police station with a speed of 20 km/hr at intervals of 10 minutes.A man coming from opposite direction towards the police station meets the jeep at an interval of 8 minutes.Find the speed of the man. ",
        "answer" : "5 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two city A and B are 27 km away. Two buses start from A and B in the same direction with speed 24 km/hr and 18 km/hr respectively. Both meet at point C beyond B. Find the distance BC. ",
        "answer" : " 81 km "
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man travels 800 km by train at 80 km/hr, 420 km by car at 60 km/hr and 200 km by cycle at 20 km/hr. What is the average speed of the journey? ",
        "answer" : "1420/27 km/hr "
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ram and Shyam start at the same with speed 10 km/hr and 11 km/hr respectively. ",
        "answer" : "88 km "
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person covered a certain distance at some speed. Had he moved 4 km/hr faster, he would have taken 30 minutes less. If he had moved 3 km/hr slower, he would have taken 30 minutes more. Find the distance (in km) ",
        "answer" : "84 km "
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ram and Shyam start from the same place P at same time towards Q, which are 60km apart. Ram’s speed is 4 km/hr more than that of Shyam.Ram turns back after reaching Q and meet Shyam at 12 km distance from Q.Find the speed of Shyam. ",
        "answer" : "8 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A and B run a kilometre and A wins by 20 second. A and C run a kilometre and A wins by 250 m. When B and C run the same distance, B wins by 25 second. The time taken by A to run a kilometre is ",
        "answer" : "2 min 15 second"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person crosses a 600 m long street in 5 minutes. What is his speed in km per hour?",
        "answer" : "7.2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "An aeroplane covers a certain distance at a speed of 240 kmph in 5 hours. To cover the same distance in 1(2/3)hours, it must travel at a speed of:",
        "answer" : "720 kmph"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If a person walks at 14 km/hr instead of 10 km/hr, he would have walked 20 km more. The actual distance travelled by him is:",
        "answer" : "50 km"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A train can travel 50% faster than a car. Both start from point A at the same time and reach point B 75 kms away from A at the same time. On the way, however, the train lost about 12.5 minutes while stopping at the stations. The speed of the car is:",
        "answer" : "120 kmph"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Excluding stoppages, the speed of a bus is 54 kmph and including stoppages, it is 45 kmph. For how many minutes does the bus stop per hour?",
        "answer" : "10"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a flight of 600 km, an aircraft was slowed down due to bad weather. Its average speed for the trip was reduced by 200 km/hr and the time of flight increased by 30 minutes. The duration of the flight is:",
        "answer" : "1 hour"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man complete a journey in 10 hours. He travels first half of the journey at the rate of 21 km/hr and second half at the rate of 24 km/hr. Find the total journey in km.",
        "answer" : "224 km"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio between the speeds of two trains is 7 : 8. If the second train runs 400 km in 4 hours, then the speed of the first train is:",
        "answer" : "87.5 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man on tour travels first 160 km at 64 km/hr and the next 160 km at 80 km/hr. The average speed for the first 320 km of the tour is:",
        "answer" : "71.11 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A car travelling with 5/7 of its actual speed covers 42 km in 1 hr 40 min 48 sec. Find the actual speed of the car.",
        "answer" : "35 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio between the speeds of two trains is 7 : 8. If the second train runs 400 km in 4 hours, then the speed of the first train is:",
        "answer" : "87.5 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In covering a distance of 30 km, Abhay takes 2 hours more than Sameer. If Abhay doubles his speed, then he would take 1 hour less than Sameer. Abhay's speed is:",
        "answer" : "5 kmph"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Robert is travelling on his cycle and has calculated to reach point A at 2 P.M. if he travels at 10 kmph, he will reach there at 12 noon if he travels at 15 kmph. At what speed must he travel to reach A at 1 P.M.?",
        "answer" : "12 kmph"
    },
    {
        "question" : "It takes eight hours for a 600 km journey, if 120 km is done by train and the rest by car. It takes 20 minutes more, if 200 km is done by train and the rest by car. The ratio of the speed of the train to that of the cars is:",
        "answer" : "3 : 4"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A farmer travelled a distance of 61 km in 9 hours. He travelled partly on foot @ 4 km/hr and partly on bicycle @ 9 km/hr. The distance travelled on foot is:",
        "answer" : "16 km"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man covered a certain distance at some speed. Had he moved 3 kmph faster, he would have taken 40 minutes less. If he had moved 2 kmph slower, he would have taken 40 minutes more. The distance (in km) is:",
        "answer" : "40"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person travels from one place to another at 30 km/hr and returns at 120 km/hr. If the total time taken is 5 hours, then find the Distance.",
        "answer" : "120 km"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Traveling at 3/4th of the original Speed a train is 10 minutes late. Find the usual Time taken by the train to complete the journey?",
        "answer" : "30 minutes."
    },
    {
        "question" : "After traveling 50km, a train meets with an accident and travels at (3/4)th of the usual Speed and reaches 45 min late. Had the accident happened 10km further on it would have reached 35 min late. Find the usual Speed?",
        "answer" : "20 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man travels from his home to office at 4km/hr and reaches his office 20 min late. If the Speed had been 6 km/hr he would have reached 10 min early. Find the distance from his home to office.",
        "answer" : "6 km"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ram can row a boat in still water at 10 kmph. He decides to go boating in a river. To row upstream he takes 2 hours and to row downstream he takes 1 ½ hours. Find the Speed of the river.",
        "answer" : "10/7 kmph"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ram and Shyam are standing at two ends of a room with a width of 30 m. They start walking towards each other along the width of the room with a Speed of 2 m/s and 1 m/s, respectively. Find the total distance travelled by Ram when he meets Shyam for the third time.",
        "answer" : "400m"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man decided to cover a distance of 6 km in 84 minutes. He decided to cover two thirds of the distance at 4 km / hr and the remaining at some different speed. Find the speed after the two third distance has been covered.",
        "answer" : "5 kmph"
    },
    {
        "question" : "While going to office, Ramesh travels at a speed of 30 kmph and on his way back, he travels at a speed of 45 kmph. What is his average speed of the whole journey?",
        "answer" : "36 kmph"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person crosses a 600 m long street in 5 minutes, What is his speed in km per hour?",
        "answer" : "7.2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The speed of a car increases by 2 kms after every one hour. If the distance travelling in the first one hour was 35 kms. what was the total distance travelled in 12 hours?",
        "answer" : "552 kms"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A thief is noticed by a policeman from a distance of 200 m. The thief starts running and the policeman chases him. The thief and the policeman run at the rate of 10 km and 11 km per hour respectively. What is the distance between them after 6 minutes?",
        "answer" : "100 m"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man on tour travels first 160 km at 64 km/hr and the next 160 km at 80 km/hr. The average speed for the first 320 km of the tour is",
        "answer" : "71.11 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two trains A and B start simultaneously in the opposite direction from two points P and Q and arrive at their destinations 16 and 9 hours respectively after their meeting each other. At what speed does the second train B travel if the first train travels at 120 km/h",
        "answer" : "160 km/h"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man reaches his office 20 min late, if he walks from his home at 3 km per hour and reaches 30 min early if he walks 4 km per hour. How far is his office from his house ?",
        "answer" : "10 km"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two horses start trotting towards each other, one from A to B and another from B to A. They cross each other after one hour and the first horse reaches B, 5/6 hour before the second horse reaches A. If the distance between A and B is 50 km. what is the speed of the slower horse?",
        "answer" : "20 km/h"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The ratio between the speeds of two trains is 7: 8. If the second train runs 400 kms in 4 hours, then the speed of the first train is ?",
        "answer" : " 87.5 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How long will a boy take to run round a square field of side 35 meters, If he runs at the rate of 9 km/hr?",
        "answer" : "56 sec"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The distance of the college and home of Rajeev is 80km. One day he was late by 1 hour than the normal time to leave for the college, so he increased his speed by 4km/h and thus he reached  to college  at the normal time. What is the changed (or increased) speed of Rajeev?",
        "answer" : "20 km/h"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man walking at the rate of 5 km/hr crosses a bridge in 15 minutes. The length of the bridge (in metres) is",
        "answer" : "1250"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Akash leaves mumbai at 6 am and reaches Bangalore  at  10 am . Prakash leaves Bangalore at 8 am and reaches Mumbai at 11:30 am. At what time do they cross each other?",
        "answer" : "8:56 am"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man traveled from the village to the post-office at the rate of 25 kmph and walked back at the rate of 4 kmph. If the whole journey took 5 hours 48 minutes, find the distance of the post-office from the village ?",
        "answer" : "20 km"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man walks 6 km at a speed of 1(1/2) kmph, runs 8 km at a speed of 2 kmph and goes by bus another 32 km. Speed of the bus is 8 kmph. Find the average speed of the man in kmph.",
        "answer" : "54/13 kmph"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If Deepesh had walked 20 km/h faster he woulh have saved 1 hour in the distance of 60km. what is the usual speed of Deepesh?",
        "answer" : "100"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two trains starting at the same time from two stations 200 km apart and going in opposite directions cross each other at a distance of 110 km from one of the stations. What is the ratio of their speeds?",
        "answer" : " 11 : 9"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man takes 6 hours 15 minutes in walking a distance and riding back to the starting place. He could walk both ways in 7 hours 45 minutes. The time taken by him to ride both ways, is ",
        "answer" : " 4 hours 45 minutes"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two persons start running simultaneously around a circular track of length 300 m from the same point at speeds of 15 km/hr and 25 km/hr. When will they meet for the first time any where on the track if they are moving in opposite directions  ?",
        "answer" : " 27 sec"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man covers half of his journey by train at 60 km/hr, half of the remaining by bus at 30 km/hr and the rest by cycle at 10 km/hr. Find his average speed during the entire journey?",
        "answer" : "24 kmph"
    },
    {
        "question" : "An employee may claim Rs. 7.00 for each km when he travels by taxi and Rs. 6.00 for each km if he drives his own car. If in one week he claimed Rs. 595 for traveling 90 km. How many kms did he travel by taxi ?",
        "answer" : "55 kms"
    },
    {
        "question" : "With an average speed of 40 km/hr, a train reaches its destination in time. If it goes with an average speed of 35 km/hr, it is late by 15 minutes. Find the length of the total journey?",
        "answer" : "70 kms"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a one km race A gives B a start of 100m and in a one km race B gives a start of 80 m to C. In a 1 km race who will win and by how much distance from the worst performer between two losers?",
        "answer" : "172 m"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A train overtakes two girls who are walking in the  opposite direction in which the train  is going at the rate of 3 km/h and 6km/h and passes them completely in 36 seconds and 30 seconds respectively. The length of the train is:",
        "answer" : " 150m"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The distance between two cities A and B is 330 Km. A train starts from A at 8 a.m. and travel towards B at 60 km/hr. Another train starts from B at 9 a.m and travels towards A at 75 Km/hr. At what time do they meet?",
        "answer" : "11 a.m"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A thief goes away with a MARUTHI car at a speed of 40 kmph. The theft has been discovered after half an hour and the owner sets off in a bike at 50 kmph when will the owner over take the thief from the start ?",
        "answer" : "2 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two boys starting from the same place walk at a rate of 5kmph and 5.5kmph respectively. What time will they take to be 8.5km apart, if they walk in the same direction?",
        "answer" : "17 hours"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person takes 20 minutes more to cover a certain distance by decreasing his speed by 20%. What is the time taken to cover the distance at his original speed ?",
        "answer" : "1 hr 20 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person goes to his office at 1/3rd of the speed at which he returns from his office. If the average speed during the whole trip is 12 m /h . what is the speed of the person while he was going to his office?",
        "answer" : "8"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The number of degrees that the hour hand of a clock moves through between noon and 2.30 in the afternoon of the same day is",
        "answer" : " 75"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man covers a distance of 1200 km in 70 days resting 9 hours a day, if he rests 10 hours a day and walks with speed 1½ times of the previous in how many days will he cover 840 km ?",
        "answer" : "35 days"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man whose speed is 4.5 kmph in still water rows to a certain upstream point and back to the starting point in a river which flows at 1.5 kmph, find his average speed for the total journey ?",
        "answer" : "4 kmph"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The distance from town A to town B is five miles. C is six miles from B. Which of the following could be the maximum distance from A to C?",
        "answer" : "11"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two bike riders ride in opposite directions around a circular track, starting at the same time from the same point. Biker A rides at a speed of 16 kmph and biker B rides at a speed of 14 kmph. If the track has a diameter of 40 km, after how much time (in hours) will the two bikers meet?",
        "answer" : " 4.18"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Excluding stoppages, the average speed of a bus is 60 km/hr and including stoppages, the average speed of the bus is 40 km/hr. For how many minutes does the bus stop per hour ?",
        "answer" : "20 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A Person X started at 3 hours earlier  at 40km/h from a place P, then another person Y followed him at 60km/h. Started his journey at 3 O'clock, afternoon. What is the diference in time when X was30 km ahead of Y and when Y was 30 km ahead of X?",
        "answer" : "3h"
    },
    {
        "question" : "P is faster than Q. P and Q each walk 24 km. The sum of their speeds is 7 km/hr and the sum of times taken by them is 14 hours. Then, P's speed is equal to ?",
        "answer" : " 4 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two men A and B start from place X walking at 4 ½ kmph and 5 ¾ kmph respectively. How many km apart they are at the end of 3 ½ hours if they are walking in the same direction ?",
        "answer" : "35/8 km"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A train of length 250 m crosses a bridge of length 150m in 20 seconds. What is the speed of train?",
        "answer" : "72 km/h"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A train covers a distance in 50 minutes, if it runs at a speed of 48kmph on an average. Find the speed at which the train must run to reduce the time of journey to 40 minutes.",
        "answer" : "60 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man in a train notices that he can count 41 telephone posts in one minute. If they are known to be 50 metres apart, then at what speed is the train travelling?",
        "answer" : "120 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A son and father goes for boating in river upstream . After rowing for 1 mile son notices the hat of his father falling in the river. After 5 min he tells his father that his hat has fallen. So they turn round and are able to pick the hat at the point from where they began boating after 5min. Find the speed of river  in miles/hours ?",
        "answer" : "6 mile/hr"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Jagan went to another town covering 240 km by car moving at 60 kmph. Then he covered 400km by train moving at 100 kmph and then rest 200 km he covered by a bus moving at 50 kmph. The average speed during the whole journey was ?",
        "answer" : "70 kmph"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Shahrukh starts from Barabanki to Fatehpur , 1 hour after Ajay starts. Shahrukh meets Kajol 1.5 hours after Shahrukh starts. If the speed of Shahrukh is at least 20km/h faster than the speed of Kajol. What is the minimum speed of Shahrukh to overtake Ajay, before he meets Kajol?",
        "answer" : "67.5 km/h "
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ashwin fires two bullets from the same place at an interval of 15 minutes but Rahul sitting in a bus approaching the place hears the second sound 14 minutes 30 seconds after the first. If sound travels at the speed of 330 meter per second, what is the approximate speed of bus?",
        "answer" : " 330/29 m/s"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Arjun and Bhishma are running on a circular track of length 600m. Speed of Arjun is 30 m/s and that of Bhishma is 20 m/s .They start fro the same point at the same time in the same direction. When will they meet again for the first time?",
        "answer" : " 60 sec."
    },
    {
        "question" : "A and B runs around a circular track. A beats B by one round or 10 minutes. In this race, they had completed 4 rounds. If the race was only of one round, find the A's time over the course:",
        "answer" : "7.5 min"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two persons start running simultaneously around a circular track of length 600 m from the same point at speeds of 25 kmph and 35 kmph. When will they meet for the first time any where on the track  ?",
        "answer" : "36 sec"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man walks at a speed of 2 km/hr and runs at a speed of 6 km/hr. How much time will the man require to cover a distance of 20 1/2 km, if he completes half of the distance, i.e., (10 1/4) km on foot and the other half by running ?",
        "answer" : " 11.9 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Ali travels a distance of 300 m in 2 minutes and 30 seconds. What is his speed in Kmph?",
        "answer" : " 7.2"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Vipin crosses a 450 metres wide road in 9 seconds. What is his speed (in km/hr)?",
        "answer" : " 180"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A machine puts c caps on bottles in m minutes. How many hours will it take to put caps on b bottles",
        "answer" : "bm/60c"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man covered a certain distance at some speed. Had he moved 3 kmph faster, he would have taken 40 minutes less. If he had moved 2 kmph slower, he would have taken 40 minutes more. The distance (in km) is ",
        "answer" : " 40"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Running 3/4th of his usual rate, a man is 15min late. Find his usual time in hours  ?",
        "answer" : "3/4 hrs"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A man is riding a bike with front and back wheel circumference of 40 inches and 70 inches respectively. If the man rides the bike on a straight road without slippage, how many inches will the man have travelled when the front wheel has made 15 revolutions more than the back wheel?",
        "answer" : "1400"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A bus covers its journey at the speed of 80km/hr in 10hours. If the same distance is to be covered in 4 hours, by how much the speed of bus will have to increase ?",
        "answer" : "120 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question" : "P, Q and R start simultaneously from A to B. P reaches B, turns back and meet Q at a distance of 11 km from B. Q reached B, turns back and meet R at a distance of 9 km from B. If the ratio of the speeds of P and R is 3:2, what is the distance between A and B ?",
        "answer" : "99"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Mr. Karthik drives to work at an average speed of 48 km/hr. Time taken to cover the first 60% of the distance is 20 minutes more than the time taken to cover the remaining distance. Then how far is his office ?",
        "answer" : "80 km"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two motor bikes cover the same distance at the speed of 60 and 64 kmps respectively. Find the distance traveled by them if the slower bike takes 1 hour more than the faster bike ?",
        "answer" : "960 km"
    },
    {
        "question" : "K and L starts walking towards each other at 4 pm at speed of 3 km/hr and 4 km/hr respectively. They were initially 17.5 km apart. At what time do they meet ?",
        "answer" : " 6:30 pm"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Buses start from a bus terminal with a speed of 20 km/hr at intervals of 10 minutes. What is the speed of a man coming from the opposite direction towards the bus terminal if he meets the buses at intervals of 8 minutes?",
        "answer" : "5 kmph"
    },
    {
        "question" : "If Hema walks at 12 km/hr instead of 8 km/hr, she would have walked 20 km more. The actual distance travelled by Hema is ?",
        "answer" : "40 kms"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A person travels from K to L a speed of 50 km/hr and returns by increasing his speed by 50%. What is his average speed for both the trips ?",
        "answer" : " 60 kmph"
    },
    {
        "question" : " A train covers 180 km distance in 5 hours. Another train covers the same distance in 1 hour less. What is the difference in the distances covered by these trains in one hour if they are moving in the same direction?",
        "answer" : "9 kms"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In what time a 360 m. long train moving at the speed of 44 km/hr will cross a 140 m. long bridge ?",
        "answer" : "41 sec"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two trains start from same place at same time at right angles to each other. Their speeds are 36km/hr and 48km/hr respectively. After 30 seconds the distance between them will be ?",
        "answer" : "500 mts"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Robert is traveling on his cycle and has calculated to reach point A at 2 p.m. if he travels at 10 km/hr; he will reach there at 12 noon if he travels at 15 km/hr. At what speed must he travel to reach A at 1 p.m. ?",
        "answer" : "12 kmph"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two stations A and B are 200 km apart on a straight track. One train starts from A at 7 a.m. and travels towards B at 20 kmph. Another train starts from B at 8 a.m. and travels towards A at a speed of 25 kmph. At what time will they meet?",
        "answer" : "12 p.m."
    },
    {
        "question" : "If a girl cycles at 10 kmph, then she arrives at a certain place at 1 p.m. If she cycles at 15 kmph, she will arrive at the same place at 11 a.m. At what speed must she cycle to get there at noon?",
        "answer" : "12 kmph"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Two trains 85 m and 75 m long are running in same direction with speeds of 62 km/hr and 44 km/hr respectively. In what time will the first train cross the second train ?",
        "answer" : "32 sec"
    },
    {
        "question" : "A 200 m long train passes a motorcycler, running in the same direction at 12 km/hr, in 15 second and a jeep travelling in the same direction in 20 s. At what speed is the car travelling (length of both the motorcycler and jeep is negligible)?",
        "answer" : " 24 kmph"
    },
    {
        "question" : "In a race of 800m Kaushik gives Piyush a start of 200m and then loses the race by 20 seconds. What is the speed of Piyush and Kaushik respectively ? If the ratio of respective speeds be 3:2",
        "answer" : "20 m/s"
    },
    {
        "question" : "You drive to the store at 20 kmph and return by the same route at 30 kmph. Discounting the time spent at the store, what was your average speed ?",
        "answer" : "24 kmph"
    }

]